#document_id:The Harmonicon_1828-005_ms_1
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:An unfortunate intrigue with a lady of royal birth, having obliged Jarnowick to quit France @ la sourdine, in the year 1780, his situation was filled by the incomparable Viotti, whom the author of Les Jardins, Delille, used to call the “ Pindar of the Violin.”
An	O	_	an	DET
unfortunate	O	_	unfortunate	ADJ
intrigue	O	_	intrigue	NOUN
with	O	_	with	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
lady	O	_	lady	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
royal	O	_	royal	ADJ
birth	O	_	birth	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
having	O	_	having	AUX
obliged	O	_	oblige	VERB
Jarnowick	B-person	Q1526160	Jarnowick	PROPN
to	O	_	to	PART
quit	O	_	quit	VERB
France	B-country	Q142	France	PROPN
@	O	_	@	X
la	O	_	la	X
sourdine	O	_	sourdine	X
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
year	O	_	year	NOUN
1780	O	_	1780	NUM
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
his	O	_	his	PRON
situation	O	_	situation	NOUN
was	O	_	be	AUX
filled	O	_	fill	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
incomparable	O	_	incomparable	ADJ
Viotti	B-person	Q313188	Viotti	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
whom	O	_	whom	PRON
the	O	_	the	DET
author	O	_	author	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Les	B-book	NIL	Les	PROPN
Jardins	I-book	NIL	Jardins	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Delille	B-person	Q981922	Delille	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
used	O	_	use	VERB
to	O	_	to	PART
call	O	_	call	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Pindar	B-nan	NIL	Pindar	PROPN
of	I-nan	NIL	of	ADP
the	I-nan	NIL	the	DET
Violin	I-nan	NIL	Violin	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Quarterly_Musical_Magazine_And_Review_ms_1827-034_1_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:As Italian music is strengthened by the adoption of accompaniments written in the style of Haydn and Mozart, -as the operas of Rossini are enjoyed at Vienna and at Berlin, nearly as much as at Naples and Milan, it is probable that thirty years hence there will be but one style of Mugisseurs.
As	O	_	as	SCONJ
Italian	O	_	italian	ADJ
music	O	_	music	NOUN
is	O	_	be	AUX
strengthened	O	_	strengthen	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
adoption	O	_	adoption	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
accompaniments	O	_	accompaniment	NOUN
written	O	_	write	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
style	O	_	style	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Haydn	B-person	Q7349	Haydn	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Mozart	B-person	Q254	Mozart	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
-as	O	_	-as	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
operas	O	_	opera	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Rossini	B-person	Q9726	Rossini	PROPN
are	O	_	be	AUX
enjoyed	O	_	enjoy	VERB
at	O	_	at	ADP
Vienna	B-city	Q1741	Vienna	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
at	O	_	at	ADP
Berlin	B-city	Q64	Berlin	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
nearly	O	_	nearly	ADV
as	O	_	as	ADV
much	O	_	much	ADV
as	O	_	as	ADP
at	O	_	at	ADP
Naples	B-city	Q2634	Naples	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Milan	B-city	Q490	Milan	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
it	O	_	it	PRON
is	O	_	be	AUX
probable	O	_	probable	ADJ
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
thirty	O	_	thirty	NUM
years	O	_	year	NOUN
hence	O	_	hence	ADV
there	O	_	there	PRON
will	O	_	will	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
but	O	_	but	ADV
one	O	_	one	NUM
style	O	_	style	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Mugisseurs	O	_	mugisseur	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Quarterly_Musical_Magazine_And_Review_ms_1826-030_4_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Miss Sterling, a young Jady not more than 17 years of age, a pupil of Mr. Neate, played Mr. Moscheles’ fantasia on. the air, “ du clair de la lune,” with such uncommon brilliancy of finger and excellence of style as to do equal honour to her own industry, and to the care even of so fine a master as Mr. Neate.
Miss	B-person	NIL	Miss	PROPN
Sterling	I-person	NIL	Sterling	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
a	O	_	a	DET
young	O	_	young	ADJ
Jady	O	_	Jady	PROPN
not	O	_	not	PART
more	O	_	more	ADJ
than	O	_	than	ADP
17	O	_	17	NUM
years	O	_	year	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
age	O	_	age	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
a	O	_	a	DET
pupil	O	_	pupil	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Mr.	B-person	Q18526894	Mr.	PROPN
Neate	I-person	Q18526894	Neate	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
played	O	_	play	VERB
Mr.	B-person	Q159551	Mr.	PROPN
Moscheles	I-person	Q159551	Moscheles	PROPN
’	O	_	’	PART
fantasia	O	_	fantasia	NOUN
on	O	_	on	ADP
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
air	O	_	air	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
du	B-music	NIL	du	X
clair	I-music	NIL	clair	X
de	I-music	NIL	de	X
la	I-music	NIL	la	X
lune	I-music	NIL	lune	X
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
with	O	_	with	ADP
such	O	_	such	ADJ
uncommon	O	_	uncommon	ADJ
brilliancy	O	_	brilliancy	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
finger	O	_	finger	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
excellence	O	_	excellence	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
style	O	_	style	NOUN
as	O	_	as	SCONJ
to	O	_	to	PART
do	O	_	do	VERB
equal	O	_	equal	ADJ
honour	O	_	honour	NOUN
to	O	_	to	ADP
her	O	_	her	PRON
own	O	_	own	ADJ
industry	O	_	industry	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
care	O	_	care	NOUN
even	O	_	even	ADV
of	O	_	of	ADP
so	O	_	so	ADV
fine	O	_	fine	ADJ
a	O	_	a	DET
master	O	_	master	NOUN
as	O	_	as	ADP
Mr.	B-person	Q18526894	Mr.	PROPN
Neate	I-person	Q18526894	Neate	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_Times_ms_1896-646_2_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The foundation of the Church Orchestral Society, by the Honourable Richard Strutt, and the hearty support given it by Sir John Stainer, has furthered im great measure this desirable movement, and its. progress has been assisted in no small degree by the individual efforts. of organists, whose endeavours deserve cordial: commendation.
The	O	_	the	DET
foundation	O	_	foundation	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Church	B-organization	NIL	Church	PROPN
Orchestral	I-organization	NIL	Orchestral	PROPN
Society	I-organization	NIL	Society	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
by	O	_	by	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Honourable	O	_	Honourable	PROPN
Richard	B-person	Q75270792	Richard	PROPN
Strutt	I-person	Q75270792	Strutt	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
hearty	O	_	hearty	ADJ
support	O	_	support	NOUN
given	O	_	give	VERB
it	O	_	it	PRON
by	O	_	by	ADP
Sir	B-person	Q1388550	Sir	PROPN
John	I-person	Q1388550	John	PROPN
Stainer	I-person	Q1388550	Stainer	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
has	O	_	have	AUX
furthered	O	_	further	VERB
i	O	_	i	ADP
m	O	_	m	ADP
great	O	_	great	ADJ
measure	O	_	measure	NOUN
this	O	_	this	DET
desirable	O	_	desirable	ADJ
movement	O	_	movement	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
its	O	_	its	PRON
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
progress	O	_	progress	NOUN
has	O	_	have	AUX
been	O	_	be	AUX
assisted	O	_	assist	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
no	O	_	no	DET
small	O	_	small	ADJ
degree	O	_	degree	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
individual	O	_	individual	ADJ
efforts	O	_	effort	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
of	O	_	of	ADP
organists	O	_	organist	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
whose	O	_	whose	DET
endeavours	O	_	endeavour	NOUN
deserve	O	_	deserve	VERB
cordial	O	_	cordial	ADJ
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
commendation	O	_	commendation	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:Dwight's Journal of Music_1853-026_ms_1
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Tlow nearly the ‘violence of these factions might, have approached to’ that of: the Ghibellines against the Guelphs, or of the Orsini against the Colonna, had time been granted them, it is intpossible to say, for the sinews of the war were cut by the “reconciliation that came to pass between the tenor and the -prima donna.
Tlow	O	_	tlow	ADJ
nearly	O	_	nearly	ADV
the	O	_	the	DET
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
violence	O	_	violence	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
these	O	_	these	DET
factions	O	_	faction	NOUN
might	O	_	might	AUX
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
have	O	_	have	AUX
approached	O	_	approach	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
that	O	_	that	PRON
of	O	_	of	ADP
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
Ghibellines	B-organization	Q187742	Ghibellines	PROPN
against	O	_	against	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Guelphs	B-organization	Q187742	Guelphs	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
or	O	_	or	CCONJ
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Orsini	B-family	Q855303	Orsini	PROPN
against	O	_	against	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Colonna	B-family	Q327202	Colonna	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
had	O	_	have	AUX
time	O	_	time	NOUN
been	O	_	be	AUX
granted	O	_	grant	VERB
them	O	_	they	PRON
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
it	O	_	it	PRON
is	O	_	be	AUX
intpossible	O	_	intpossible	ADJ
to	O	_	to	PART
say	O	_	say	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
for	O	_	for	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
sinews	O	_	sinew	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
war	O	_	war	NOUN
were	O	_	be	AUX
cut	O	_	cut	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
reconciliation	O	_	reconciliation	NOUN
that	O	_	that	PRON
came	O	_	come	VERB
to	O	_	to	PART
pass	O	_	pass	VERB
between	O	_	between	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
tenor	O	_	tenor	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
-prima	O	_	-prima	ADJ
donna	O	_	donna	X
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_Times_ms_1896-646_3_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:We advisedly say “our”! distinguished pianist, because forty-five years of residence in this country, and of unbroken hard work in our English schools of music, the Royal Academy, Royal College, Guildhall School, and the tentative National Training School entitle Mr. Pauer to the citizenship of our land as well as the gratitude of all those who know how important and. widespread his influence has been.
We	O	_	we	PRON
advisedly	O	_	advisedly	ADV
say	O	_	say	VERB
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
our	O	_	our	PRON
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
!	O	_	!	PUNCT
distinguished	O	_	distinguished	ADJ
pianist	O	_	pianist	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
because	O	_	because	SCONJ
forty	O	_	forty	NUM
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
five	O	_	five	NUM
years	O	_	year	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
residence	O	_	residence	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
this	O	_	this	DET
country	O	_	country	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
of	O	_	of	ADP
unbroken	O	_	unbroken	ADJ
hard	O	_	hard	ADJ
work	O	_	work	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
our	O	_	our	PRON
English	O	_	english	ADJ
schools	O	_	school	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
music	O	_	music	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
Royal	B-school	Q1144673	Royal	PROPN
Academy	I-school	Q1144673	Academy	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Royal	B-school	Q304985	Royal	PROPN
College	I-school	Q304985	College	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Guildhall	B-school	Q1419737	Guildhall	PROPN
School	I-school	Q1419737	School	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
tentative	O	_	tentative	ADJ
National	B-school	Q55082727	National	PROPN
Training	I-school	Q55082727	Training	PROPN
School	I-school	Q55082727	School	PROPN
entitle	O	_	entitle	VERB
Mr.	B-person	Q79183	Mr.	PROPN
Pauer	I-person	Q79183	Pauer	PROPN
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
citizenship	O	_	citizenship	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
our	O	_	our	PRON
land	O	_	land	NOUN
as	O	_	as	ADV
well	O	_	well	ADV
as	O	_	as	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
gratitude	O	_	gratitude	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
all	O	_	all	DET
those	O	_	those	PRON
who	O	_	who	PRON
know	O	_	know	VERB
how	O	_	how	SCONJ
important	O	_	important	ADJ
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
widespread	O	_	widespread	ADJ
his	O	_	his	PRON
influence	O	_	influence	NOUN
has	O	_	have	AUX
been	O	_	be	AUX
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_World_ms_1855-025_1_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:John of Procida was among the most active leaders in this revolt, and his name and exploits, forming the theme of many a poem and romance, have now been celebrated by MM. Scribe and Verdi in the opera of Les Vépres Siciliennes.
John	B-person	Q1227361	John	PROPN
of	I-person	Q1227361	of	ADP
Procida	I-person	Q1227361	Procida	PROPN
was	O	_	be	AUX
among	O	_	among	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
most	O	_	most	ADV
active	O	_	active	ADJ
leaders	O	_	leader	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
this	O	_	this	DET
revolt	O	_	revolt	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
his	O	_	his	PRON
name	O	_	name	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
exploits	O	_	exploit	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
forming	O	_	form	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
theme	O	_	theme	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
many	O	_	many	DET
a	O	_	a	DET
poem	O	_	poem	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
romance	O	_	romance	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
have	O	_	have	AUX
now	O	_	now	ADV
been	O	_	be	AUX
celebrated	O	_	celebrate	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
MM	B-person	NIL	MM	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
Scribe	O	_	Scribe	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Verdi	B-person	Q7317	Verdi	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
opera	O	_	opera	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Les	B-opera	Q471645	Les	PROPN
Vépres	I-opera	Q471645	Vépres	PROPN
Siciliennes	I-opera	Q471645	Siciliennes	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:Dwight's Journal of Music_1857-001_ms_3
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Nevertheless, the house was crowded, and the performances, consisting of a miscellaneous concert. by the orchestra, Thalberg, d’Angri, and various German singing societies, (the best of which, however, had withdrawn their servi, ces in view of the above-mentioned condition), and the first act of Fidelio.
Nevertheless	O	_	nevertheless	ADV
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
house	O	_	house	NOUN
was	O	_	be	AUX
crowded	O	_	crowded	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
performances	O	_	performance	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
consisting	O	_	consist	VERB
of	O	_	of	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
miscellaneous	O	_	miscellaneous	ADJ
concert	O	_	concert	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
by	O	_	by	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
orchestra	O	_	orchestra	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Thalberg	B-person	Q347871	Thalberg	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
d’Angri	B-person	Q5358988	d’Angri	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
various	O	_	various	ADJ
German	O	_	german	ADJ
singing	O	_	singing	NOUN
societies	O	_	society	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
(	O	_	(	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
best	O	_	good	ADJ
of	O	_	of	ADP
which	O	_	which	PRON
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
however	O	_	however	ADV
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
had	O	_	have	AUX
withdrawn	O	_	withdraw	VERB
their	O	_	their	PRON
servi	O	_	servi	X
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
ces	O	_	ces	X
in	O	_	in	ADP
view	O	_	view	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
above	O	_	above	ADV
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
mentioned	O	_	mention	VERB
condition	O	_	condition	NOUN
)	O	_	)	PUNCT
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
first	O	_	first	ADJ
act	O	_	act	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Fidelio	B-work-of-art	Q193778	Fidelio	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1823-002_ms_4
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:About’ this time, too, he rejected:an offer from an amateur of Paris, which commissioned him to produce a vocal composition after the manner of Rameau and‘Lulli, passages of their works being at thesame.time sent to. him as models.
About	O	_	about	ADP
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
this	O	_	this	DET
time	O	_	time	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
too	O	_	too	ADV
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
he	O	_	he	PRON
rejected	O	_	reject	VERB
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
an	O	_	an	DET
offer	O	_	offer	NOUN
from	O	_	from	ADP
an	O	_	an	DET
amateur	O	_	amateur	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Paris	B-city	Q90	Paris	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
which	O	_	which	PRON
commissioned	O	_	commission	VERB
him	O	_	he	PRON
to	O	_	to	PART
produce	O	_	produce	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
vocal	O	_	vocal	ADJ
composition	O	_	composition	NOUN
after	O	_	after	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
manner	O	_	manner	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Rameau	B-person	Q1145	Rameau	PROPN
and‘Lulli	O	_	and‘Lulli	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
passages	O	_	passage	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
their	O	_	their	PRON
works	O	_	work	NOUN
being	O	_	be	AUX
at	O	_	at	ADP
thesame.time	O	_	thesame.time	ADJ
sent	O	_	send	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
him	O	_	he	PRON
as	O	_	as	ADP
models	O	_	model	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:Dwight's Journal of Music_1855-002_ms_3
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Below Schandau you pass the bold promontory of Schramstein, close sunder the fortified heights of Pfaffenstein, and ‘Konigstein with its impregnable fortress—against whose walls Napoleon battered: in vain—thence on, through a wild country of tale-telling tradition, “thé cradle of gnomes and. kobolds,”’ till, at length, near Dresden you emerge among thriving . Villages and cultivated fields; like the exit, on the.Neckar, from the vallies of Odenwald upon the plains of the Rhine at Heidelberg.
Below	O	_	below	ADP
Schandau	O	_	Schandau	PROPN
you	O	_	you	PRON
pass	O	_	pass	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
bold	O	_	bold	ADJ
promontory	O	_	promontory	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Schramstein	B-mountain	Q878205	Schramstein	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
close	O	_	close	ADV
sunder	O	_	sunder	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
fortified	O	_	fortified	ADJ
heights	O	_	height	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Pfaffenstein	B-mountain	Q453233	Pfaffenstein	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
Konigstein	B-city	Q6783	Konigstein	PROPN
with	O	_	with	ADP
its	O	_	its	PRON
impregnable	O	_	impregnable	ADJ
fortress	O	_	fortress	NOUN
—	O	_	—	PUNCT
against	O	_	against	ADP
whose	O	_	whose	DET
walls	O	_	wall	NOUN
Napoleon	B-person	Q517	Napoleon	PROPN
battered	O	_	batter	VERB
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
vain	O	_	vain	ADJ
—	O	_	—	PUNCT
thence	O	_	thence	ADV
on	O	_	on	ADP
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
through	O	_	through	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
wild	O	_	wild	ADJ
country	O	_	country	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
tale	O	_	tale	NOUN
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
telling	O	_	tell	VERB
tradition	O	_	tradition	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
thé	O	_	thé	X
cradle	O	_	cradle	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
gnomes	O	_	gnome	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
kobolds	O	_	kobold	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
till	O	_	till	SCONJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
at	O	_	at	ADP
length	O	_	length	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
near	O	_	near	ADP
Dresden	B-city	Q1731	Dresden	PROPN
you	O	_	you	PRON
emerge	O	_	emerge	VERB
among	O	_	among	ADP
thriving	O	_	thrive	VERB
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
Villages	O	_	village	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
cultivated	O	_	cultivate	VERB
fields	O	_	field	NOUN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
like	O	_	like	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
exit	O	_	exit	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
on	O	_	on	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
.	O	_	.	PROPN
Neckar	B-river	Q1673	Neckar	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
from	O	_	from	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
vallies	O	_	vallie	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Odenwald	B-mountain	Q8359	Odenwald	PROPN
upon	O	_	upon	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
plains	O	_	plain	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Rhine	B-river	Q584	Rhine	PROPN
at	O	_	at	ADP
Heidelberg	B-city	Q2966	Heidelberg	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Quarterly_Musical_Magazine_And_Review_ms_1826-030_5_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Until the appearance of Lully’s overtures such a prelude was never thought of, and what is even more singular, by their novelty and excellence, they continued for a long time to hold their place and pre-eminence, and were played before operas composed by Vinci, Leo, and Pergolesi, nearly a century after the date of their original production.
Until	O	_	until	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
appearance	O	_	appearance	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Lully	B-person	Q1192	Lully	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
overtures	O	_	overture	NOUN
such	O	_	such	DET
a	O	_	a	DET
prelude	O	_	prelude	NOUN
was	O	_	be	AUX
never	O	_	never	ADV
thought	O	_	think	VERB
of	O	_	of	ADP
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
what	O	_	what	PRON
is	O	_	be	AUX
even	O	_	even	ADV
more	O	_	more	ADV
singular	O	_	singular	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
by	O	_	by	ADP
their	O	_	their	PRON
novelty	O	_	novelty	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
excellence	O	_	excellence	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
they	O	_	they	PRON
continued	O	_	continue	VERB
for	O	_	for	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
long	O	_	long	ADJ
time	O	_	time	NOUN
to	O	_	to	PART
hold	O	_	hold	VERB
their	O	_	their	PRON
place	O	_	place	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
pre	O	_	pre	NOUN
-	O	_	-	NOUN
eminence	O	_	eminence	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
were	O	_	be	AUX
played	O	_	play	VERB
before	O	_	before	ADP
operas	O	_	opera	NOUN
composed	O	_	compose	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
Vinci	B-person	Q29577	Vinci	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Leo	B-person	Q316735	Leo	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Pergolesi	B-person	Q185312	Pergolesi	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
nearly	O	_	nearly	ADV
a	O	_	a	DET
century	O	_	century	NOUN
after	O	_	after	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
date	O	_	date	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
their	O	_	their	PRON
original	O	_	original	ADJ
production	O	_	production	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:Dwight's Journal of Music_1854-002_ms_2
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:His brightest years were those divided betwixt London and Paris, <when he formed one of the quartet-with Madame Grisi, Signori Lablache and Tamburini; his most luerdtive | professional’ days were possibly those last ones spent in St. Petersburgh, where H- M. the-Czar, to do him honor, made him Colonel of a regiment.
His	O	_	his	PRON
brightest	O	_	bright	ADJ
years	O	_	year	NOUN
were	O	_	be	AUX
those	O	_	those	PRON
divided	O	_	divide	VERB
betwixt	O	_	betwixt	ADP
London	B-city	Q84	London	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Paris	B-city	Q90	Paris	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
<	O	_	<	X
when	O	_	when	SCONJ
he	O	_	he	PRON
formed	O	_	form	VERB
one	O	_	one	NUM
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
quartet	O	_	quartet	NOUN
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
with	O	_	with	ADP
Madame	B-person	Q287344	Madame	PROPN
Grisi	I-person	Q287344	Grisi	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Signori	O	_	Signori	PROPN
Lablache	O	_	Lablache	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Tamburini	B-person	Q605376	Tamburini	PROPN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
his	O	_	his	PRON
most	O	_	most	ADV
luerdtive	O	_	luerdtive	ADJ
|	O	_	|	PUNCT
professional	O	_	professional	ADJ
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
days	O	_	day	NOUN
were	O	_	be	AUX
possibly	O	_	possibly	ADV
those	O	_	those	DET
last	O	_	last	ADJ
ones	O	_	one	NOUN
spent	O	_	spend	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
St.	O	_	St.	PROPN
Petersburgh	O	_	Petersburgh	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
where	O	_	where	SCONJ
H-	O	_	H-	PROPN
M.	O	_	M.	PROPN
the	O	_	the	DET
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
Czar	O	_	Czar	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
to	O	_	to	PART
do	O	_	do	VERB
him	O	_	he	PRON
honor	O	_	honor	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
made	O	_	make	VERB
him	O	_	he	PRON
Colonel	O	_	Colonel	PROPN
of	O	_	of	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
regiment	O	_	regiment	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Musical Times_1853-106_ms_2
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The connecting link between Mozart the dramatic composer, and Mozart in his Masses, was « Mr. Frank Novello, formerly prompter at the Opera in the palmy days of Taylor’s management, and also principal bass at the Portuguese Ambassador's Chapel in South-street, Grosvenor-square, where his brother was organist.
The	O	_	the	DET
connecting	O	_	connect	VERB
link	O	_	link	NOUN
between	O	_	between	ADP
Mozart	B-person	Q254	Mozart	PROPN
the	O	_	the	DET
dramatic	O	_	dramatic	ADJ
composer	O	_	composer	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Mozart	B-person	Q254	Mozart	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
his	O	_	his	PRON
Masses	O	_	masse	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
was	O	_	be	AUX
«	O	_	«	PUNCT
Mr.	B-person	NIL	Mr.	PROPN
Frank	I-person	NIL	Frank	PROPN
Novello	I-person	NIL	Novello	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
formerly	O	_	formerly	ADV
prompter	O	_	prompter	NOUN
at	O	_	at	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Opera	B-nan	NIL	Opera	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
palmy	O	_	palmy	ADJ
days	O	_	day	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Taylor	B-person	NIL	Taylor	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
management	O	_	management	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
also	O	_	also	ADV
principal	O	_	principal	ADJ
bass	O	_	bass	NOUN
at	O	_	at	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Portuguese	B-worship-place	NIL	Portuguese	PROPN
Ambassador	I-worship-place	NIL	Ambassador	PROPN
's	I-worship-place	NIL	's	PART
Chapel	I-worship-place	NIL	Chapel	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
South	O	_	South	PROPN
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
street	O	_	street	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Grosvenor	B-location	Q932992	Grosvenor	PROPN
-	I-location	Q932992	-	PUNCT
square	I-location	Q932992	square	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
where	O	_	where	SCONJ
his	O	_	his	PRON
brother	O	_	brother	NOUN
was	O	_	be	AUX
organist	O	_	organist	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_World__ms_1844-005_2_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Would the students in the London University be satisfied with Professor Morgan, if, in what he designated a course of lectures on Mathematics, he were content to regale them with a narrative of the life and adventures of Hermogenes—the birth and parentage of Euclid—the amours and idiosyncracies of Cardan the burning alive of Giordano Bruno and Vanini the simplicity and ingenious nature of the moral character of Spinoza—or the interesting peculiarities of Sir Isaac Newton’s dog?
Would	O	_	would	AUX
the	O	_	the	DET
students	O	_	student	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
London	B-university	Q170027	London	PROPN
University	O	_	University	PROPN
be	O	_	be	AUX
satisfied	O	_	satisfied	ADJ
with	O	_	with	ADP
Professor	O	_	Professor	PROPN
Morgan	B-person	NIL	Morgan	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
if	O	_	if	SCONJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
what	O	_	what	PRON
he	O	_	he	PRON
designated	O	_	designate	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
course	O	_	course	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
lectures	O	_	lecture	NOUN
on	O	_	on	ADP
Mathematics	O	_	mathematic	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
he	O	_	he	PRON
were	O	_	be	AUX
content	O	_	content	ADJ
to	O	_	to	PART
regale	O	_	regale	VERB
them	O	_	they	PRON
with	O	_	with	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
narrative	O	_	narrative	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
life	O	_	life	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
adventures	O	_	adventure	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Hermogenes	B-person	NIL	Hermogenes	PROPN
—	O	_	—	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
birth	O	_	birth	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
parentage	O	_	parentage	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Euclid	B-person	Q8747	Euclid	PROPN
—	O	_	—	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
amours	O	_	amour	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
idiosyncracies	O	_	idiosyncracie	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Cardan	B-person	Q184530	Cardan	PROPN
the	O	_	the	DET
burning	O	_	burn	VERB
alive	O	_	alive	ADJ
of	O	_	of	ADP
Giordano	B-person	Q36330	Giordano	PROPN
Bruno	I-person	Q36330	Bruno	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Vanini	B-person	Q553128	Vanini	PROPN
the	O	_	the	DET
simplicity	O	_	simplicity	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
ingenious	O	_	ingenious	ADJ
nature	O	_	nature	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
moral	O	_	moral	ADJ
character	O	_	character	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Spinoza	B-person	Q35802	Spinoza	PROPN
—	O	_	—	PUNCT
or	O	_	or	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
interesting	O	_	interesting	ADJ
peculiarities	O	_	peculiarity	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Sir	B-person	Q935	Sir	PROPN
Isaac	I-person	Q935	Isaac	PROPN
Newton	I-person	Q935	Newton	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
dog	O	_	dog	NOUN
?	O	_	?	PUNCT

#document_id:the_Musical_Times_ms_1895-634_3_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The rumour that the Church Choral Society will not sing this season has received recent confirmation, and this, if true, will leave the field in New York for choruses of moderate size open to the Musical Art Society (under Mr. Frank Damrosch), the New York Musical Society (under Mr. Dossert), and the new Harlem Oratorio Society.
The	O	_	the	DET
rumour	O	_	rumour	NOUN
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
Church	B-organization	NIL	Church	PROPN
Choral	I-organization	NIL	Choral	PROPN
Society	I-organization	NIL	Society	PROPN
will	O	_	will	AUX
not	O	_	not	PART
sing	O	_	sing	VERB
this	O	_	this	DET
season	O	_	season	NOUN
has	O	_	have	AUX
received	O	_	receive	VERB
recent	O	_	recent	ADJ
confirmation	O	_	confirmation	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
this	O	_	this	PRON
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
if	O	_	if	SCONJ
true	O	_	true	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
will	O	_	will	AUX
leave	O	_	leave	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
field	O	_	field	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
New	B-city	Q60	New	PROPN
York	I-city	Q60	York	PROPN
for	O	_	for	ADP
choruses	O	_	chorus	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
moderate	O	_	moderate	ADJ
size	O	_	size	NOUN
open	O	_	open	ADJ
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Musical	B-organization	NIL	Musical	PROPN
Art	I-organization	NIL	Art	PROPN
Society	I-organization	NIL	Society	PROPN
(	O	_	(	PUNCT
under	O	_	under	ADP
Mr.	B-person	Q962237	Mr.	PROPN
Frank	I-person	Q962237	Frank	PROPN
Damrosch	I-person	Q962237	Damrosch	PROPN
)	O	_	)	PUNCT
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
New	B-organization	NIL	New	PROPN
York	I-organization	NIL	York	PROPN
Musical	I-organization	NIL	Musical	PROPN
Society	I-organization	NIL	Society	PROPN
(	O	_	(	PUNCT
under	O	_	under	ADP
Mr.	B-person	NIL	Mr.	PROPN
Dossert	I-person	NIL	Dossert	PROPN
)	O	_	)	PUNCT
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
new	O	_	new	ADJ
Harlem	B-organization	NIL	Harlem	PROPN
Oratorio	I-organization	NIL	Oratorio	PROPN
Society	I-organization	NIL	Society	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1823-002_ms_3
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:La Clemenza di Tito was the first, in which‘a French lady, under the riame of Signora Clarini, took the part of Servilia, and a Madame’ Graziani filled the character ef Annio, both of which were massacred in their hands, and the whole opera necessarily partook in the-ruin.
La	B-opera	Q578526	La	PROPN
Clemenza	I-opera	Q578526	Clemenza	PROPN
di	I-opera	Q578526	di	PROPN
Tito	I-opera	Q578526	Tito	PROPN
was	O	_	be	AUX
the	O	_	the	DET
first	O	_	first	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
which‘a	O	_	which‘a	PRON
French	B-nan	NIL	french	ADJ
lady	I-nan	NIL	lady	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
under	O	_	under	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
riame	O	_	riame	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Signora	B-person	NIL	Signora	PROPN
Clarini	I-person	NIL	Clarini	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
took	O	_	take	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
part	O	_	part	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Servilia	O	_	Servilia	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
a	O	_	a	DET
Madame	O	_	Madame	PROPN
’	O	_	’	PART
Graziani	O	_	Graziani	PROPN
filled	O	_	fill	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
character	O	_	character	NOUN
ef	B-nan	NIL	ef	ADP
Annio	I-nan	NIL	Annio	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
both	O	_	both	PRON
of	O	_	of	ADP
which	O	_	which	PRON
were	O	_	be	AUX
massacred	O	_	massacre	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
their	O	_	their	PRON
hands	O	_	hand	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
whole	O	_	whole	ADJ
opera	O	_	opera	NOUN
necessarily	O	_	necessarily	ADV
partook	O	_	partake	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
ruin	O	_	ruin	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Quarterly_Musical_Magazine_And_Review_ms_1827-022_2_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Both however appeared we believe at last at Dr. Crotch’s, though. but for the very kind assistance of Madame Caradori, the poor Doctor would have had no little difficulty in-getting his Pavestine per- formed, notwithstanding it had been so long separately and specially announced that both Miss Stephens and Miss Paton were engaged to sing in it.
Both	O	_	both	PRON
however	O	_	however	ADV
appeared	O	_	appear	VERB
we	O	_	we	PRON
believe	O	_	believe	VERB
at	O	_	at	ADP
last	O	_	last	ADV
at	O	_	at	ADP
Dr.	B-person	Q718709	Dr.	PROPN
Crotch	I-person	Q718709	Crotch	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
though	O	_	though	ADV
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
for	O	_	for	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
very	O	_	very	ADV
kind	O	_	kind	ADJ
assistance	O	_	assistance	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Madame	B-person	Q16065895	Madame	PROPN
Caradori	I-person	Q16065895	Caradori	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
poor	O	_	poor	ADJ
Doctor	O	_	Doctor	PROPN
would	O	_	would	AUX
have	O	_	have	AUX
had	O	_	have	VERB
no	O	_	no	DET
little	O	_	little	ADJ
difficulty	O	_	difficulty	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
getting	O	_	get	VERB
his	O	_	his	PRON
Pavestine	O	_	Pavestine	PROPN
per-	O	_	per-	ADV
formed	O	_	form	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
notwithstanding	O	_	notwithstanding	SCONJ
it	O	_	it	PRON
had	O	_	have	AUX
been	O	_	be	AUX
so	O	_	so	ADV
long	O	_	long	ADV
separately	O	_	separately	ADV
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
specially	O	_	specially	ADV
announced	O	_	announce	VERB
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
both	O	_	both	DET
Miss	B-person	Q5052928	Miss	PROPN
Stephens	I-person	Q5052928	Stephens	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Miss	B-person	Q16888398	Miss	PROPN
Paton	I-person	Q16888398	Paton	PROPN
were	O	_	be	AUX
engaged	O	_	engage	VERB
to	O	_	to	PART
sing	O	_	sing	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
it	O	_	it	PRON
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:the_Musical_Times_ms_1896-635_12_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The principal novelty of the Concert on the 1st ult. was “La Naissance de Venus,’ scéne mythologique, by M. Paul Collin, set to music by M.G. Fauré, an important work carefully scored, but wanting in the charm to which this .graceful composer has accustomed us.
The	O	_	the	DET
principal	O	_	principal	ADJ
novelty	O	_	novelty	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Concert	O	_	Concert	PROPN
on	O	_	on	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
1st	O	_	1st	ADJ
ult	O	_	ult	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
was	O	_	be	AUX
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
La	B-music	NIL	La	PROPN
Naissance	I-music	NIL	naissance	NOUN
de	I-music	NIL	de	ADP
Venus	I-music	NIL	Venus	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
scéne	O	_	scéne	X
mythologique	O	_	mythologique	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
by	O	_	by	ADP
M.	B-person	Q3370911	M.	PROPN
Paul	I-person	Q3370911	Paul	PROPN
Collin	I-person	Q3370911	Collin	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
set	O	_	set	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
music	O	_	music	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
M.G.	O	_	M.G.	PROPN
Fauré	O	_	Fauré	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
an	O	_	an	DET
important	O	_	important	ADJ
work	O	_	work	NOUN
carefully	O	_	carefully	ADV
scored	O	_	score	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
wanting	O	_	want	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
charm	O	_	charm	NOUN
to	O	_	to	PART
which	O	_	which	PRON
this	O	_	this	DET
.graceful	O	_	.graceful	ADJ
composer	O	_	composer	NOUN
has	O	_	have	AUX
accustomed	O	_	accustom	VERB
us	O	_	we	PRON
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Musical Times_1871-335_ms_2
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Once again the same very peculiar metre appears in a hymn tune which Dr. Gauntlett ascribes to one Braun (whoever he may have been) as the author, and to the year 1675 asthe date; and this coincidence, if the ascription be authentic, is as curious as the other.
Once	O	_	once	ADV
again	O	_	again	ADV
the	O	_	the	DET
same	O	_	same	ADJ
very	O	_	very	ADV
peculiar	O	_	peculiar	ADJ
metre	O	_	metre	NOUN
appears	O	_	appear	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
hymn	O	_	hymn	NOUN
tune	O	_	tune	NOUN
which	O	_	which	PRON
Dr.	O	_	Dr.	PROPN
Gauntlett	B-person	Q11925412	Gauntlett	PROPN
ascribes	O	_	ascribe	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
one	O	_	one	NUM
Braun	B-person	NIL	Braun	PROPN
(	O	_	(	PUNCT
whoever	O	_	whoever	PRON
he	O	_	he	PRON
may	O	_	may	AUX
have	O	_	have	AUX
been	O	_	be	AUX
)	O	_	)	PUNCT
as	O	_	as	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
author	O	_	author	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
year	O	_	year	NOUN
1675	O	_	1675	NUM
asthe	O	_	asthe	ADJ
date	O	_	date	NOUN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
this	O	_	this	DET
coincidence	O	_	coincidence	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
if	O	_	if	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
ascription	O	_	ascription	NOUN
be	O	_	be	VERB
authentic	O	_	authentic	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
is	O	_	be	AUX
as	O	_	as	ADV
curious	O	_	curious	ADJ
as	O	_	as	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
other	O	_	other	ADJ
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1827-002_ms_2
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The productions of Tallis, Birde, Morley, and Farrant, of Gibbons and Child, of Blow and Purcell, of Croft, Greene, Boyce, Nares, and we might add others, are not only excellent qguoad compositions, but equally perfect as forming a part of our religious worship: they never for a moment lose the true devotional character, though their difference from each other, in many respects, is as wide as the several periods at which they were written.
The	O	_	the	DET
productions	O	_	production	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Tallis	B-person	Q207789	Tallis	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Birde	B-person	Q208375	Birde	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Morley	B-person	Q438141	Morley	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Farrant	B-person	Q7325622	Farrant	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
of	O	_	of	ADP
Gibbons	B-person	Q311913	Gibbons	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Child	B-person	Q8006771	Child	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
of	O	_	of	ADP
Blow	B-person	Q311110	Blow	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Purcell	B-person	Q9695	Purcell	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
of	O	_	of	ADP
Croft	B-person	Q1236164	Croft	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Greene	B-person	Q615819	Greene	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Boyce	B-person	Q313152	Boyce	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Nares	B-person	Q463998	Nares	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
we	O	_	we	PRON
might	O	_	might	AUX
add	O	_	add	VERB
others	O	_	other	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
are	O	_	be	AUX
not	O	_	not	PART
only	O	_	only	ADV
excellent	O	_	excellent	ADJ
qguoad	O	_	qguoad	PROPN
compositions	O	_	composition	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
equally	O	_	equally	ADV
perfect	O	_	perfect	ADJ
as	O	_	as	ADP
forming	O	_	form	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
part	O	_	part	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
our	O	_	our	PRON
religious	O	_	religious	ADJ
worship	O	_	worship	NOUN
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
they	O	_	they	PRON
never	O	_	never	ADV
for	O	_	for	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
moment	O	_	moment	NOUN
lose	O	_	lose	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
true	O	_	true	ADJ
devotional	O	_	devotional	ADJ
character	O	_	character	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
though	O	_	though	SCONJ
their	O	_	their	PRON
difference	O	_	difference	NOUN
from	O	_	from	ADP
each	O	_	each	DET
other	O	_	other	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
many	O	_	many	ADJ
respects	O	_	respect	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
is	O	_	be	AUX
as	O	_	as	ADV
wide	O	_	wide	ADJ
as	O	_	as	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
several	O	_	several	ADJ
periods	O	_	period	NOUN
at	O	_	at	ADP
which	O	_	which	PRON
they	O	_	they	PRON
were	O	_	be	AUX
written	O	_	write	VERB
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Musical Times_1871-335_ms_4
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:John Bull would be a fitting name, in truth, for the composer of the English National Anthem ; the validity of the assignment, however, is stronger with reference to the people who have adopted the tune in one form and altered it into another to please themselves, than to the learned musician who composed a piece with the same number of bars.
John	B-person	Q511463	John	PROPN
Bull	I-person	Q511463	Bull	PROPN
would	O	_	would	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
a	O	_	a	DET
fitting	O	_	fitting	ADJ
name	O	_	name	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
truth	O	_	truth	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
for	O	_	for	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
composer	O	_	composer	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
English	B-music	Q327133	english	ADJ
National	I-music	Q327133	National	PROPN
Anthem	I-music	Q327133	Anthem	PROPN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
validity	O	_	validity	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
assignment	O	_	assignment	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
however	O	_	however	ADV
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
is	O	_	be	AUX
stronger	O	_	strong	ADJ
with	O	_	with	ADP
reference	O	_	reference	NOUN
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
people	O	_	people	NOUN
who	O	_	who	PRON
have	O	_	have	AUX
adopted	O	_	adopt	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
tune	O	_	tune	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
one	O	_	one	NUM
form	O	_	form	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
altered	O	_	alter	VERB
it	O	_	it	PRON
into	O	_	into	ADP
another	O	_	another	PRON
to	O	_	to	PART
please	O	_	please	VERB
themselves	O	_	themselves	PRON
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
than	O	_	than	ADP
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
learned	O	_	learned	ADJ
musician	O	_	musician	NOUN
who	O	_	who	PRON
composed	O	_	compose	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
piece	O	_	piece	NOUN
with	O	_	with	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
same	O	_	same	ADJ
number	O	_	number	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
bars	O	_	bar	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_World__ms_1843-042_3_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The rest of the concert was made up ofan exhibition on the violoncello, during which the “veteran” delighted us with “ Polly put the kettle on’—some sentimentalities by Bellini, Pacini and Zingarelli, and the worn out terzetto from Il Matrimonio Segretto, which by this time I am quite tired of, thongh Miss Marshall, Mrs. Shaw and Mrs. Bushe did it ample justice, as far as singing went—I say nothing about acting.
The	O	_	the	DET
rest	O	_	rest	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
concert	O	_	concert	NOUN
was	O	_	be	AUX
made	O	_	make	VERB
up	O	_	up	ADP
ofan	O	_	ofan	ADP
exhibition	O	_	exhibition	NOUN
on	O	_	on	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
violoncello	O	_	violoncello	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
during	O	_	during	ADP
which	O	_	which	PRON
the	O	_	the	DET
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
veteran	O	_	veteran	NOUN
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
delighted	O	_	delight	VERB
us	O	_	we	PRON
with	O	_	with	ADP
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Polly	O	_	Polly	PROPN
put	O	_	put	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
kettle	O	_	kettle	NOUN
on’—some	O	_	on’—some	PUNCT
sentimentalities	O	_	sentimentality	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
Bellini	B-person	Q170209	Bellini	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Pacini	B-person	Q357022	Pacini	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Zingarelli	B-person	Q505202	Zingarelli	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
worn	O	_	wear	VERB
out	O	_	out	ADP
terzetto	O	_	terzetto	NOUN
from	O	_	from	ADP
Il	B-music	Q428319	Il	PROPN
Matrimonio	I-music	Q428319	Matrimonio	PROPN
Segretto	I-music	Q428319	Segretto	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
which	O	_	which	PRON
by	O	_	by	ADP
this	O	_	this	DET
time	O	_	time	NOUN
I	O	_	I	PRON
am	O	_	be	AUX
quite	O	_	quite	ADV
tired	O	_	tired	ADJ
of	O	_	of	ADP
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
thongh	O	_	thongh	X
Miss	B-person	NIL	Miss	PROPN
Marshall	I-person	NIL	Marshall	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Mrs.	B-person	Q3291051	Mrs.	PROPN
Shaw	I-person	Q3291051	Shaw	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Mrs.	B-person	NIL	Mrs.	PROPN
Bushe	I-person	NIL	Bushe	PROPN
did	O	_	do	VERB
it	O	_	it	PRON
ample	O	_	ample	ADJ
justice	O	_	justice	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
as	O	_	as	ADV
far	O	_	far	ADV
as	O	_	as	SCONJ
singing	O	_	singing	NOUN
went	O	_	go	VERB
—	O	_	—	PUNCT
I	O	_	I	PRON
say	O	_	say	VERB
nothing	O	_	nothing	PRON
about	O	_	about	ADP
acting	O	_	acting	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1832-006_ms_3
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:In the twenty-fifth number of our new series (January 1830), appeared a review of a work of great science, learning, and merit, under the title of Instructions to my Daughter for Playing on the Enharmonic Guitar, written by Lieutenant-Colonel Perronet.
In	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
twenty	O	_	twenty	NUM
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
fifth	O	_	fifth	ADJ
number	O	_	number	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
our	O	_	our	PRON
new	O	_	new	ADJ
series	O	_	series	NOUN
(	O	_	(	PUNCT
January	O	_	January	PROPN
1830	O	_	1830	NUM
)	O	_	)	PUNCT
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
appeared	O	_	appear	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
review	O	_	review	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
work	O	_	work	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
great	O	_	great	ADJ
science	O	_	science	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
learning	O	_	learning	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
merit	O	_	merit	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
under	O	_	under	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
title	O	_	title	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Instructions	O	_	Instructions	PROPN
to	O	_	to	ADP
my	O	_	my	PRON
Daughter	O	_	daughter	NOUN
for	O	_	for	ADP
Playing	O	_	play	VERB
on	O	_	on	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Enharmonic	O	_	Enharmonic	PROPN
Guitar	O	_	Guitar	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
written	O	_	write	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
Lieutenant	O	_	Lieutenant	PROPN
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
Colonel	O	_	Colonel	PROPN
Perronet	B-person	Q4670375	Perronet	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_World__ms_1845-029_2_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:We may mention as a remarkable circumstance, that on the evening of the night on which he was born, his mother, notwithstanding the delicacy of her situation, was induced to go to a concert given by Paganini at the Teatro Santo Augustino in Genoa; when the performance of the great Maestro produced such an effect on her mind and nerves as to precipitate her accouchement, and the young Sivori came into the world somewhat before his time.
We	O	_	we	PRON
may	O	_	may	AUX
mention	O	_	mention	VERB
as	O	_	as	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
remarkable	O	_	remarkable	ADJ
circumstance	O	_	circumstance	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
on	O	_	on	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
evening	O	_	evening	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
night	O	_	night	NOUN
on	O	_	on	ADP
which	O	_	which	PRON
he	O	_	he	PRON
was	O	_	be	AUX
born	O	_	bear	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
his	O	_	his	PRON
mother	O	_	mother	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
notwithstanding	O	_	notwithstanding	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
delicacy	O	_	delicacy	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
her	O	_	her	PRON
situation	O	_	situation	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
was	O	_	be	AUX
induced	O	_	induce	VERB
to	O	_	to	PART
go	O	_	go	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
concert	O	_	concert	NOUN
given	O	_	give	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
Paganini	B-person	Q66075	Paganini	PROPN
at	O	_	at	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Teatro	B-building	Q19060499	Teatro	PROPN
Santo	I-building	Q19060499	Santo	PROPN
Augustino	I-building	Q19060499	Augustino	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
Genoa	B-city	Q1449	Genoa	PROPN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
when	O	_	when	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
performance	O	_	performance	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
great	O	_	great	ADJ
Maestro	O	_	Maestro	PROPN
produced	O	_	produce	VERB
such	O	_	such	DET
an	O	_	an	DET
effect	O	_	effect	NOUN
on	O	_	on	ADP
her	O	_	her	PRON
mind	O	_	mind	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
nerves	O	_	nerve	NOUN
as	O	_	as	SCONJ
to	O	_	to	PART
precipitate	O	_	precipitate	VERB
her	O	_	her	PRON
accouchement	O	_	accouchement	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
young	O	_	young	ADJ
Sivori	B-person	Q1029423	Sivori	PROPN
came	O	_	come	VERB
into	O	_	into	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
world	O	_	world	NOUN
somewhat	O	_	somewhat	ADV
before	O	_	before	ADP
his	O	_	his	PRON
time	O	_	time	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:the_Musical_Times_ms_1896-635_6_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:At a second Advent Service, on the 12th ult., the “Last Judgment” of Spohr was. given, but without an orchestra, its place being filled at the organ as efficiently as it could be by Mr. G. R. Sinclair, the organist of Hereford Cathedral.
At	O	_	at	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
second	O	_	second	ADJ
Advent	B-event	Q83012	Advent	PROPN
Service	O	_	Service	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
on	O	_	on	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
12th	O	_	12th	ADJ
ult	O	_	ult	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Last	B-music	NIL	last	ADJ
Judgment	I-music	NIL	judgment	NOUN
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
of	O	_	of	ADP
Spohr	B-person	Q57226	Spohr	PROPN
was	O	_	be	AUX
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
given	O	_	give	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
without	O	_	without	ADP
an	O	_	an	DET
orchestra	O	_	orchestra	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
its	O	_	its	PRON
place	O	_	place	NOUN
being	O	_	be	AUX
filled	O	_	fill	VERB
at	O	_	at	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
organ	O	_	organ	NOUN
as	O	_	as	ADV
efficiently	O	_	efficiently	ADV
as	O	_	as	SCONJ
it	O	_	it	PRON
could	O	_	could	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
by	O	_	by	ADP
Mr.	B-person	Q5543957	Mr.	PROPN
G.	I-person	Q5543957	G.	PROPN
R.	I-person	Q5543957	R.	PROPN
Sinclair	I-person	Q5543957	Sinclair	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
organist	O	_	organist	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Hereford	B-building	Q429379	Hereford	PROPN
Cathedral	I-building	Q429379	Cathedral	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_Times_ms_1905-754_7_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:At Ann’s Road Church, Heeley, Sterndale Bennett’s ‘ May Queen’ formed one of a series of admirable services: and concerts, and Oxford Street Chapel, another suburban centre of musical activity, was the /oca/e of a particularly good all-round performance of ‘The Creation’ under Mr. Joseph Kaye.
At	O	_	at	ADP
Ann	B-road	NIL	Ann	PROPN
’s	I-road	NIL	’s	PART
Road	I-road	NIL	Road	PROPN
Church	I-road	NIL	Church	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Heeley	B-city-district	Q5697963	Heeley	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Sterndale	B-person	Q201164	Sterndale	PROPN
Bennett	I-person	Q201164	Bennett	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
May	B-music	NIL	May	PROPN
Queen	I-music	NIL	Queen	PROPN
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
formed	O	_	form	VERB
one	O	_	one	NUM
of	O	_	of	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
series	O	_	series	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
admirable	O	_	admirable	ADJ
services	O	_	service	NOUN
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
concerts	O	_	concert	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Oxford	O	_	Oxford	PROPN
Street	O	_	Street	PROPN
Chapel	O	_	Chapel	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
another	O	_	another	DET
suburban	O	_	suburban	ADJ
centre	O	_	centre	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
musical	O	_	musical	ADJ
activity	O	_	activity	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
was	O	_	be	AUX
the	O	_	the	DET
/oca	O	_	/oca	X
/	O	_	/	X
e	O	_	e	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
particularly	O	_	particularly	ADV
good	O	_	good	ADJ
all	O	_	all	ADV
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
round	O	_	round	ADJ
performance	O	_	performance	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
The	B-music	NIL	the	DET
Creation	I-music	NIL	creation	NOUN
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
under	O	_	under	ADP
Mr.	B-person	NIL	Mr.	PROPN
Joseph	I-person	NIL	Joseph	PROPN
Kaye	I-person	NIL	Kaye	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1826-048_ms_4
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Two of these compositions have been published, and are as follows :— Morgengruss an Goethe, &y., (Morning Salutation to Goéthe on his Birth-day) ; the poetry by F. W. Riemar, the music for two sopranos, tenor and basy by C. Eberwein, with an aceompaniment for the piano, (Bpth in score, andin parts.)
Two	O	_	two	NUM
of	O	_	of	ADP
these	O	_	these	DET
compositions	O	_	composition	NOUN
have	O	_	have	AUX
been	O	_	be	AUX
published	O	_	publish	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
are	O	_	be	AUX
as	O	_	as	SCONJ
follows	O	_	follow	VERB
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
—	O	_	—	PUNCT
Morgengruss	O	_	Morgengruss	PROPN
an	O	_	an	PRON
Goethe	B-person	Q5879	Goethe	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
&	O	_	&	PROPN
y.	O	_	y.	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
(	O	_	(	PUNCT
Morning	B-publication	NIL	morning	NOUN
Salutation	I-publication	NIL	salutation	NOUN
to	I-publication	NIL	to	ADP
Goéthe	I-publication	NIL	Goéthe	PROPN
on	O	_	on	ADP
his	O	_	his	PRON
Birth	O	_	birth	NOUN
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
day	O	_	day	NOUN
)	O	_	)	PUNCT
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
poetry	O	_	poetry	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
F.	B-person	Q85393	F.	PROPN
W.	I-person	Q85393	W.	PROPN
Riemar	I-person	Q85393	Riemar	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
music	O	_	music	NOUN
for	O	_	for	ADP
two	O	_	two	NUM
sopranos	O	_	soprano	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
tenor	O	_	tenor	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
basy	O	_	basy	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
C.	B-person	Q216234	C.	PROPN
Eberwein	I-person	Q216234	Eberwein	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
with	O	_	with	ADP
an	O	_	an	DET
aceompaniment	O	_	aceompaniment	NOUN
for	O	_	for	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
piano	O	_	piano	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
(	O	_	(	PUNCT
Bpth	O	_	bpth	X
in	O	_	in	ADP
score	O	_	score	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
andin	O	_	andin	ADP
parts	O	_	part	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
)	O	_	)	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1830-003_ms_2
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Madame Kraus-Wranisky is a singer superior to Madame Seidler, both in power and expression, although she is occasionally defective in execution; and, spite of a homely look and large person, does every thing with a grace and dignity strongly reminding me of Pasta.
Madame	B-person	Q6373188	Madame	PROPN
Kraus	I-person	Q6373188	Kraus	PROPN
-	I-person	Q6373188	-	PUNCT
Wranisky	I-person	Q6373188	Wranisky	PROPN
is	O	_	be	AUX
a	O	_	a	DET
singer	O	_	singer	NOUN
superior	O	_	superior	ADJ
to	O	_	to	ADP
Madame	O	_	Madame	PROPN
Seidler	B-person	Q6373188	Seidler	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
both	O	_	both	PRON
in	O	_	in	ADP
power	O	_	power	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
expression	O	_	expression	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
although	O	_	although	SCONJ
she	O	_	she	PRON
is	O	_	be	AUX
occasionally	O	_	occasionally	ADV
defective	O	_	defective	ADJ
in	O	_	in	ADP
execution	O	_	execution	NOUN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
spite	O	_	spite	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
homely	O	_	homely	ADJ
look	O	_	look	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
large	O	_	large	ADJ
person	O	_	person	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
does	O	_	do	VERB
every	O	_	every	DET
thing	O	_	thing	NOUN
with	O	_	with	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
grace	O	_	grace	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
dignity	O	_	dignity	NOUN
strongly	O	_	strongly	ADV
reminding	O	_	remind	VERB
me	O	_	I	PRON
of	O	_	of	ADP
Pasta	B-person	Q240963	Pasta	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Quarterly_Musical_Magazine_And_Review_ms_1827-036_2_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:As a prima donna, Mademoiselle Lalande reminds me of Madame: Ronzi di Begnis in the force andenergy of her style; but, with an equality of talent as a musician and a charming person, as an actress she falls far short in the comparison.
As	O	_	as	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
prima	O	_	prima	NOUN
donna	O	_	donna	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Mademoiselle	B-person	NIL	Mademoiselle	PROPN
Lalande	I-person	NIL	Lalande	PROPN
reminds	O	_	remind	VERB
me	O	_	I	PRON
of	O	_	of	ADP
Madame	O	_	Madame	PROPN
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
Ronzi	B-person	Q3266332	Ronzi	PROPN
di	I-person	Q3266332	di	PROPN
Begnis	I-person	Q3266332	Begnis	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
force	O	_	force	NOUN
andenergy	O	_	andenergy	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
her	O	_	her	PRON
style	O	_	style	NOUN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
with	O	_	with	ADP
an	O	_	an	DET
equality	O	_	equality	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
talent	O	_	talent	NOUN
as	O	_	as	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
musician	O	_	musician	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
a	O	_	a	DET
charming	O	_	charming	ADJ
person	O	_	person	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
as	O	_	as	ADP
an	O	_	an	DET
actress	O	_	actress	NOUN
she	O	_	she	PRON
falls	O	_	fall	VERB
far	O	_	far	ADV
short	O	_	short	ADV
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
comparison	O	_	comparison	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_Times_ms_1905-754_9_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The Choral Society opened its sixteenth season in the Drill Hall on November 2 with a complete Elgar programme : ‘The Black Knight,’ ‘The Banner of St. George,’ ‘Imperial March,’ ‘In Hammersbach’ (from ‘The Bavarian Highlands’), and the ‘ Pomp and Circumstance’ March No. 1.
The	O	_	the	DET
Choral	B-organization	NIL	Choral	PROPN
Society	I-organization	NIL	Society	PROPN
opened	O	_	open	VERB
its	O	_	its	PRON
sixteenth	O	_	sixteenth	ADJ
season	O	_	season	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Drill	B-building	NIL	Drill	PROPN
Hall	I-building	NIL	Hall	PROPN
on	O	_	on	ADP
November	O	_	November	PROPN
2	O	_	2	NUM
with	O	_	with	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
complete	O	_	complete	ADJ
Elgar	B-person	Q179631	Elgar	PROPN
programme	O	_	programme	NOUN
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
The	B-music	Q7718359	the	DET
Black	I-music	Q7718359	black	ADJ
Knight	I-music	Q7718359	Knight	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
The	B-music	NIL	the	DET
Banner	I-music	NIL	Banner	PROPN
of	I-music	NIL	of	ADP
St.	I-music	NIL	St.	PROPN
George	I-music	NIL	George	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
Imperial	B-music	NIL	Imperial	PROPN
March	I-music	NIL	March	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
In	B-music	NIL	in	ADP
Hammersbach	I-music	NIL	Hammersbach	PROPN
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
(	O	_	(	PUNCT
from	O	_	from	ADP
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
The	O	_	the	DET
Bavarian	B-music	Q5505606	Bavarian	PROPN
Highlands	I-music	Q5505606	Highlands	PROPN
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
)	O	_	)	PUNCT
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
Pomp	O	_	pomp	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Circumstance	O	_	circumstance	NOUN
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
March	O	_	March	PROPN
No	O	_	No	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PROPN
1	O	_	1	NUM
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:Dwight's Journal of Music_1852-019_ms_2
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:From evounds ‘of reflection, the Opera Seria; to which he had paid the tribute of - his youth, accompanied by thé most brilliant suc“cess, in Italy, disgusted him ; and he began to reflect radically upon the conditions .of lyric I al tragedy, triéd to bring them ‘into application in his Orfeo, and developed them in writing in the {L preface to his Aleeste, which he dedicated to the ii grand* duke of Tuscany.
From	O	_	from	ADP
evounds	O	_	evound	NOUN
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
of	O	_	of	ADP
reflection	O	_	reflection	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
Opera	B-music	Q210675	Opera	PROPN
Seria	I-music	Q210675	Seria	PROPN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
to	O	_	to	ADP
which	O	_	which	PRON
he	O	_	he	PRON
had	O	_	have	AUX
paid	O	_	pay	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
tribute	O	_	tribute	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
his	O	_	his	PRON
youth	O	_	youth	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
accompanied	O	_	accompany	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
thé	O	_	thé	PRON
most	O	_	most	ADV
brilliant	O	_	brilliant	ADJ
suc“cess	O	_	suc“cess	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
Italy	B-country	Q38	Italy	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
disgusted	O	_	disgust	VERB
him	O	_	he	PRON
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
he	O	_	he	PRON
began	O	_	begin	VERB
to	O	_	to	PART
reflect	O	_	reflect	VERB
radically	O	_	radically	ADV
upon	O	_	upon	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
conditions	O	_	condition	NOUN
.of	O	_	.of	ADP
lyric	O	_	lyric	ADJ
I	O	_	I	PROPN
al	O	_	al	PROPN
tragedy	O	_	tragedy	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
triéd	O	_	triéd	X
to	O	_	to	PART
bring	O	_	bring	VERB
them	O	_	they	PRON
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
into	O	_	into	ADP
application	O	_	application	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
his	O	_	his	PRON
Orfeo	B-work-of-art	NIL	Orfeo	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
developed	O	_	develop	VERB
them	O	_	they	PRON
in	O	_	in	ADP
writing	O	_	write	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
{	O	_	{	PUNCT
L	O	_	l	NOUN
preface	O	_	preface	NOUN
to	O	_	to	ADP
his	O	_	his	PRON
Aleeste	O	_	Aleeste	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
which	O	_	which	PRON
he	O	_	he	PRON
dedicated	O	_	dedicate	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
ii	O	_	ii	ADJ
grand	O	_	grand	ADJ
*	O	_	*	ADJ
duke	O	_	duke	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Tuscany	O	_	Tuscany	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_World__ms_1844-005_1_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:We read, in a cotemporary, some cogent observations in reply to the “ Morning Post,” on the subject of the Professorship, which we transfer, in part, to our pages :— were to dilate profusely on the Mystéres de Parts of our worthy friend Eugéne Sue, and the profound morality of Soulié’s Memoires du Diable—what would be the result ?
We	O	_	we	PRON
read	O	_	read	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
cotemporary	O	_	cotemporary	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
some	O	_	some	DET
cogent	O	_	cogent	ADJ
observations	O	_	observation	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
reply	O	_	reply	NOUN
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Morning	B-magazine	Q1750567	Morning	PROPN
Post	I-magazine	Q1750567	Post	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
on	O	_	on	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
subject	O	_	subject	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Professorship	O	_	Professorship	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
which	O	_	which	PRON
we	O	_	we	PRON
transfer	O	_	transfer	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
part	O	_	part	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
to	O	_	to	ADP
our	O	_	our	PRON
pages	O	_	page	NOUN
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
—	O	_	—	PUNCT
were	O	_	be	AUX
to	O	_	to	PART
dilate	O	_	dilate	VERB
profusely	O	_	profusely	ADV
on	O	_	on	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Mystéres	O	_	Mystéres	PROPN
de	O	_	de	X
Parts	O	_	Parts	PROPN
of	O	_	of	ADP
our	O	_	our	PRON
worthy	O	_	worthy	ADJ
friend	O	_	friend	NOUN
Eugéne	B-person	Q315220	Eugéne	PROPN
Sue	I-person	Q315220	Sue	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
profound	O	_	profound	ADJ
morality	O	_	morality	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Soulié	B-person	Q2031275	Soulié	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
Memoires	O	_	Memoires	PROPN
du	O	_	du	X
Diable	O	_	Diable	PROPN
—	O	_	—	PUNCT
what	O	_	what	PRON
would	O	_	would	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
the	O	_	the	DET
result	O	_	result	NOUN
?	O	_	?	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_Times_ms_1905-754_2_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The Librarian of the College, the Rev. H. A. Wilson, has kindly made the following digest of a portion of-the aforesaid testamentary dispositions : Edward Ascough of Wynthorp, in his will dated 4th July, 1520, leaves all his lands in Wynthorp to his wife for her life.
The	O	_	the	DET
Librarian	O	_	Librarian	PROPN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
College	O	_	College	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
Rev.	B-person	NIL	Rev.	PROPN
H.	I-person	NIL	H.	PROPN
A.	I-person	NIL	A.	PROPN
Wilson	I-person	NIL	Wilson	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
has	O	_	have	AUX
kindly	O	_	kindly	ADV
made	O	_	make	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
following	O	_	following	ADJ
digest	O	_	digest	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
portion	O	_	portion	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
aforesaid	O	_	aforesaid	ADJ
testamentary	O	_	testamentary	ADJ
dispositions	O	_	disposition	NOUN
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
Edward	B-person	NIL	Edward	PROPN
Ascough	I-person	NIL	Ascough	PROPN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Wynthorp	O	_	Wynthorp	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
his	O	_	his	PRON
will	O	_	will	NOUN
dated	O	_	date	VERB
4th	O	_	4th	NOUN
July	O	_	July	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
1520	O	_	1520	NUM
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
leaves	O	_	leave	VERB
all	O	_	all	DET
his	O	_	his	PRON
lands	O	_	land	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
Wynthorp	O	_	Wynthorp	PROPN
to	O	_	to	ADP
his	O	_	his	PRON
wife	O	_	wife	NOUN
for	O	_	for	ADP
her	O	_	her	PRON
life	O	_	life	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_World__ms_1843-042_1_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Miss Marshall won golden opinions by her charming delivery of Gluck’s “ Che faro,” and Miss Birch, sang the superb “Ah perfido” of Beethoven better than I have ever heard it sung, except by Malibran; in the ranting air (with violin obligato) from Paer’s dull opera of Griselda, Miss Birch was no less successful, but, from the inferior nature of the composition, much less agreeable.
Miss	B-person	NIL	Miss	PROPN
Marshall	I-person	NIL	Marshall	PROPN
won	O	_	win	VERB
golden	O	_	golden	ADJ
opinions	O	_	opinion	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
her	O	_	her	PRON
charming	O	_	charming	ADJ
delivery	O	_	delivery	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Gluck	B-person	Q130759	Gluck	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Che	B-music	Q723776	Che	PROPN
faro	I-music	Q723776	faro	X
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Miss	B-person	NIL	Miss	PROPN
Birch	I-person	NIL	Birch	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
sang	O	_	sing	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
superb	O	_	superb	ADJ
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Ah	B-music	Q5661015	ah	INTJ
perfido	I-music	Q5661015	perfido	X
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
of	O	_	of	ADP
Beethoven	B-person	Q255	Beethoven	PROPN
better	O	_	well	ADV
than	O	_	than	SCONJ
I	O	_	I	PRON
have	O	_	have	AUX
ever	O	_	ever	ADV
heard	O	_	hear	VERB
it	O	_	it	PRON
sung	O	_	sing	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
except	O	_	except	SCONJ
by	O	_	by	ADP
Malibran	B-person	Q232783	Malibran	PROPN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
ranting	O	_	rant	VERB
air	O	_	air	NOUN
(	O	_	(	PUNCT
with	O	_	with	ADP
violin	O	_	violin	NOUN
obligato	O	_	obligato	NOUN
)	O	_	)	PUNCT
from	O	_	from	ADP
Paer	B-person	Q533022	Paer	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
dull	O	_	dull	ADJ
opera	O	_	opera	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Griselda	B-music	NIL	Griselda	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Miss	B-person	NIL	Miss	PROPN
Birch	I-person	NIL	Birch	PROPN
was	O	_	be	AUX
no	O	_	no	ADV
less	O	_	less	ADV
successful	O	_	successful	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
from	O	_	from	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
inferior	O	_	inferior	ADJ
nature	O	_	nature	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
composition	O	_	composition	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
much	O	_	much	ADV
less	O	_	less	ADV
agreeable	O	_	agreeable	ADJ
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:the_Musical_Times_ms_1884-493_1_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:At who think with us that the selection of operatic works for performance in any country should not be bounded by geographical restrictions, cannot but feel gratifled that the lessee of the Royal Italian Opera no longer confines himself to the creations of foreign composers; but, welcoming good music wherever it can be found, has chosen Mr. Mackenzie’s highly successful opera ‘‘ Colomba”’ as one of the chief attractions of the coming season.
At	O	_	At	NOUN
who	O	_	who	PRON
think	O	_	think	VERB
with	O	_	with	ADP
us	O	_	we	PRON
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
selection	O	_	selection	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
operatic	O	_	operatic	ADJ
works	O	_	work	NOUN
for	O	_	for	ADP
performance	O	_	performance	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
any	O	_	any	DET
country	O	_	country	NOUN
should	O	_	should	AUX
not	O	_	not	PART
be	O	_	be	AUX
bounded	O	_	bound	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
geographical	O	_	geographical	ADJ
restrictions	O	_	restriction	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
can	O	_	can	AUX
not	O	_	not	AUX
but	O	_	but	ADV
feel	O	_	feel	VERB
gratifled	O	_	gratifled	ADJ
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
lessee	O	_	lessee	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Royal	B-building	Q55018	Royal	PROPN
Italian	I-building	Q55018	Italian	PROPN
Opera	I-building	Q55018	Opera	PROPN
no	O	_	no	ADV
longer	O	_	long	ADV
confines	O	_	confine	VERB
himself	O	_	himself	PRON
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
creations	O	_	creation	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
foreign	O	_	foreign	ADJ
composers	O	_	composer	NOUN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
welcoming	O	_	welcome	VERB
good	O	_	good	ADJ
music	O	_	music	NOUN
wherever	O	_	wherever	SCONJ
it	O	_	it	PRON
can	O	_	can	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
found	O	_	find	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
has	O	_	have	AUX
chosen	O	_	choose	VERB
Mr.	B-person	Q674739	Mr.	PROPN
Mackenzie	I-person	Q674739	Mackenzie	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
highly	O	_	highly	ADV
successful	O	_	successful	ADJ
opera	O	_	opera	NOUN
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
Colomba	B-music	NIL	Colomba	PROPN
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
’	O	_	'	PUNCT
as	O	_	as	ADP
one	O	_	one	NUM
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
chief	O	_	chief	ADJ
attractions	O	_	attraction	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
coming	O	_	come	VERB
season	O	_	season	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1828-005_ms_3
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:In 1792, Jarnowick repaired to London, where he t ! : ! i played at all the great concerts till the year 1796, when the well-known dispute took place between him and J. B. Cramer, which terminated in the loss of Jarnowick’s popu Jarity in this country.
In	O	_	in	ADP
1792	O	_	1792	NUM
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Jarnowick	B-person	Q1526160	Jarnowick	PROPN
repaired	O	_	repair	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
London	B-city	Q84	London	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
where	O	_	where	SCONJ
he	O	_	he	PRON
t	O	_	t	X
!	O	_	!	PUNCT
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
!	O	_	!	PUNCT
i	O	_	I	PRON
played	O	_	play	VERB
at	O	_	at	ADP
all	O	_	all	DET
the	O	_	the	DET
great	O	_	great	ADJ
concerts	O	_	concert	NOUN
till	O	_	till	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
year	O	_	year	NOUN
1796	O	_	1796	NUM
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
when	O	_	when	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
well	O	_	well	ADV
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
known	O	_	know	VERB
dispute	O	_	dispute	NOUN
took	O	_	take	VERB
place	O	_	place	NOUN
between	O	_	between	ADP
him	O	_	he	PRON
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
J.	B-person	Q27646779	J.	PROPN
B.	I-person	Q27646779	B.	PROPN
Cramer	I-person	Q27646779	Cramer	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
which	O	_	which	PRON
terminated	O	_	terminate	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
loss	O	_	loss	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Jarnowick	B-person	Q1526160	Jarnowick	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
popu	O	_	popu	NOUN
Jarity	O	_	Jarity	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
this	O	_	this	DET
country	O	_	country	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Musical Times_1871-335_ms_3
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The strongest evidence for Carey’s claim should be an argument against it; for it isthe statement of John Christopher Smith, that Carey, unable to harmonize his own tune, asked Smith to write a bass to it; whereas in his Musical Century Carey has left plenty of proof that he was musician enough to put a very good bass to so simple a melody.
The	O	_	the	DET
strongest	O	_	strong	ADJ
evidence	O	_	evidence	NOUN
for	O	_	for	ADP
Carey	B-person	Q1606590	Carey	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
claim	O	_	claim	NOUN
should	O	_	should	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
an	O	_	an	DET
argument	O	_	argument	NOUN
against	O	_	against	ADP
it	O	_	it	PRON
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
for	O	_	for	ADP
it	O	_	it	PRON
isthe	O	_	isthe	VERB
statement	O	_	statement	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
John	B-person	Q11727869	John	PROPN
Christopher	I-person	Q11727869	Christopher	PROPN
Smith	I-person	Q11727869	Smith	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
Carey	B-person	Q1606590	Carey	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
unable	O	_	unable	ADJ
to	O	_	to	PART
harmonize	O	_	harmonize	VERB
his	O	_	his	PRON
own	O	_	own	ADJ
tune	O	_	tune	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
asked	O	_	ask	VERB
Smith	O	_	Smith	PROPN
to	O	_	to	PART
write	O	_	write	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
bass	O	_	bass	NOUN
to	O	_	to	ADP
it	O	_	it	PRON
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
whereas	O	_	whereas	SCONJ
in	O	_	in	ADP
his	O	_	his	PRON
Musical	O	_	musical	ADJ
Century	O	_	century	NOUN
Carey	B-person	Q1606590	Carey	PROPN
has	O	_	have	AUX
left	O	_	leave	VERB
plenty	O	_	plenty	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
proof	O	_	proof	NOUN
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
he	O	_	he	PRON
was	O	_	be	AUX
musician	O	_	musician	NOUN
enough	O	_	enough	ADV
to	O	_	to	PART
put	O	_	put	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
very	O	_	very	ADV
good	O	_	good	ADJ
bass	O	_	bass	NOUN
to	O	_	to	ADP
so	O	_	so	ADV
simple	O	_	simple	ADJ
a	O	_	a	DET
melody	O	_	melody	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1829-002_ms_3
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The rival of Vinci and Porpora in dramatic composition, Leo was also desirous of emulating Durante in sacred music; and as in the former department of his art he had been by turns pathetic and gay, scientific and natural, so in the latter he attained to eminence, and produced numerous compositions of a character imposing, dignified, and sublime.
The	O	_	the	DET
rival	O	_	rival	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Vinci	B-person	Q29577	Vinci	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Porpora	B-person	Q312788	Porpora	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
dramatic	O	_	dramatic	ADJ
composition	O	_	composition	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Leo	O	_	Leo	PROPN
was	O	_	be	AUX
also	O	_	also	ADV
desirous	O	_	desirous	ADJ
of	O	_	of	ADP
emulating	O	_	emulate	VERB
Durante	B-person	Q314221	Durante	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
sacred	O	_	sacred	ADJ
music	O	_	music	NOUN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
as	O	_	as	ADP
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
former	O	_	former	ADJ
department	O	_	department	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
his	O	_	his	PRON
art	O	_	art	NOUN
he	O	_	he	PRON
had	O	_	have	AUX
been	O	_	be	AUX
by	O	_	by	ADP
turns	O	_	turn	NOUN
pathetic	O	_	pathetic	ADJ
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
gay	O	_	gay	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
scientific	O	_	scientific	ADJ
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
natural	O	_	natural	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
so	O	_	so	ADV
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
latter	O	_	latter	ADJ
he	O	_	he	PRON
attained	O	_	attain	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
eminence	O	_	eminence	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
produced	O	_	produce	VERB
numerous	O	_	numerous	ADJ
compositions	O	_	composition	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
character	O	_	character	NOUN
imposing	O	_	imposing	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
dignified	O	_	dignified	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
sublime	O	_	sublime	ADJ
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Musical Times_1871-335_ms_1
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:It is a curious coincidence, to say the least of it, that an air with the same rhythmical*peculiarity—a peculiarity which is almost individualexists in a transcript of compositions by Dr. John Bull, the musical professor of Gresham College in the time of James I, and this has given occasion for the setting up in his favour of a claim to the authorship.
It	O	_	it	PRON
is	O	_	be	AUX
a	O	_	a	DET
curious	O	_	curious	ADJ
coincidence	O	_	coincidence	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
to	O	_	to	PART
say	O	_	say	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
least	O	_	least	ADJ
of	O	_	of	ADP
it	O	_	it	PRON
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
an	O	_	an	DET
air	O	_	air	NOUN
with	O	_	with	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
same	O	_	same	ADJ
rhythmical*peculiarity	O	_	rhythmical*peculiarity	NOUN
—	O	_	—	PUNCT
a	O	_	a	DET
peculiarity	O	_	peculiarity	NOUN
which	O	_	which	PRON
is	O	_	be	AUX
almost	O	_	almost	ADV
individualexists	O	_	individualexist	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
transcript	O	_	transcript	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
compositions	O	_	composition	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
Dr.	B-person	Q511463	Dr.	PROPN
John	I-person	Q511463	John	PROPN
Bull	I-person	Q511463	Bull	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
musical	O	_	musical	ADJ
professor	O	_	professor	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Gresham	B-college	Q788375	Gresham	PROPN
College	I-college	Q788375	College	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
time	O	_	time	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
James	B-person	Q79972	James	PROPN
I	I-person	Q79972	I	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
this	O	_	this	PRON
has	O	_	have	AUX
given	O	_	give	VERB
occasion	O	_	occasion	NOUN
for	O	_	for	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
setting	O	_	setting	NOUN
up	O	_	up	ADP
in	O	_	in	ADP
his	O	_	his	PRON
favour	O	_	favour	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
claim	O	_	claim	NOUN
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
authorship	O	_	authorship	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1824-020_ms_4
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Music, learned and ingenicus, like that of Jomelli, abounding in harniony and con trivance, and requiring a careful execution, and the utmost stillness and attention in the audience, would not satisfy the frivolous and depraved taste of the Italians, who used to sav, that the music of Gluck, Jomelli, Hasse, and Bach, was too rough and German.
Music	O	_	music	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
learned	O	_	learned	ADJ
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
ingenicus	O	_	ingenicus	X
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
like	O	_	like	ADP
that	O	_	that	PRON
of	O	_	of	ADP
Jomelli	B-person	Q312891	Jomelli	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
abounding	O	_	abound	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
harniony	O	_	harniony	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
con	O	_	con	X
trivance	O	_	trivance	X
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
requiring	O	_	require	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
careful	O	_	careful	ADJ
execution	O	_	execution	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
utmost	O	_	utmost	ADJ
stillness	O	_	stillness	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
attention	O	_	attention	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
audience	O	_	audience	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
would	O	_	would	AUX
not	O	_	not	PART
satisfy	O	_	satisfy	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
frivolous	O	_	frivolous	ADJ
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
depraved	O	_	depraved	ADJ
taste	O	_	taste	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Italians	O	_	Italians	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
who	O	_	who	PRON
used	O	_	use	VERB
to	O	_	to	PART
sav	O	_	sav	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
music	O	_	music	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Gluck	B-person	Q130759	Gluck	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Jomelli	B-person	Q312891	Jomelli	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Hasse	B-person	Q164732	Hasse	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Bach	B-person	Q1339	Bach	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
was	O	_	be	AUX
too	O	_	too	ADV
rough	O	_	rough	ADJ
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
German	O	_	german	ADJ
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1831-004_ms_2
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:About the middle of the fourteenth century, we may date the first symptom of taste and cultivation in the ehurch-music at Rome and Naples; it then consisted of plain-chant for four voices, sometimes aided by. a choir, and this, owing to the large size of the Italian churches, ‘was. necessarily numerous to produce any effect but the difficulty of procuring choristers was every day felt more and more.
About	O	_	about	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
middle	O	_	middle	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
fourteenth	O	_	fourteenth	ADJ
century	O	_	century	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
we	O	_	we	PRON
may	O	_	may	AUX
date	O	_	date	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
first	O	_	first	ADJ
symptom	O	_	symptom	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
taste	O	_	taste	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
cultivation	O	_	cultivation	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
ehurch	O	_	ehurch	NOUN
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
music	O	_	music	NOUN
at	O	_	at	ADP
Rome	B-city	Q220	Rome	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Naples	B-city	Q2634	Naples	PROPN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
it	O	_	it	PRON
then	O	_	then	ADV
consisted	O	_	consist	VERB
of	O	_	of	ADP
plain	O	_	plain	ADJ
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
chant	O	_	chant	NOUN
for	O	_	for	ADP
four	O	_	four	NUM
voices	O	_	voice	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
sometimes	O	_	sometimes	ADV
aided	O	_	aid	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
a	O	_	a	DET
choir	O	_	choir	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
this	O	_	this	PRON
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
owing	O	_	owe	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
large	O	_	large	ADJ
size	O	_	size	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Italian	O	_	italian	ADJ
churches	O	_	church	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
was	O	_	be	AUX
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
necessarily	O	_	necessarily	ADV
numerous	O	_	numerous	ADJ
to	O	_	to	PART
produce	O	_	produce	VERB
any	O	_	any	DET
effect	O	_	effect	NOUN
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
difficulty	O	_	difficulty	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
procuring	O	_	procure	VERB
choristers	O	_	chorister	NOUN
was	O	_	be	AUX
every	O	_	every	DET
day	O	_	day	NOUN
felt	O	_	feel	VERB
more	O	_	more	ADV
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
more	O	_	more	ADV
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:Dwight's Journal of Music_1856-001_ms_3
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:He then mentioned various compositions ot llay dn, Mozart, Beethoven, and. others, which he thinks it would be well to introduce; not the entire works, that would: perhaps be to tiresome for such..an occasion ; but the most effective and best-appreciated mov ements of thém.
He	O	_	he	PRON
then	O	_	then	ADV
mentioned	O	_	mention	VERB
various	O	_	various	ADJ
compositions	O	_	composition	NOUN
ot	O	_	ot	ADP
llay	O	_	llay	X
dn	O	_	dn	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Mozart	B-person	Q254	Mozart	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Beethoven	B-person	Q255	Beethoven	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
others	O	_	other	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
which	O	_	which	PRON
he	O	_	he	PRON
thinks	O	_	think	VERB
it	O	_	it	PRON
would	O	_	would	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
well	O	_	well	ADJ
to	O	_	to	PART
introduce	O	_	introduce	VERB
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
not	O	_	not	PART
the	O	_	the	DET
entire	O	_	entire	ADJ
works	O	_	work	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
that	O	_	that	PRON
would	O	_	would	AUX
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
perhaps	O	_	perhaps	ADV
be	O	_	be	AUX
to	O	_	to	PART
tiresome	O	_	tiresome	ADJ
for	O	_	for	ADP
such	O	_	such	ADJ
..	O	_	..	PUNCT
an	O	_	an	DET
occasion	O	_	occasion	NOUN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
most	O	_	most	ADV
effective	O	_	effective	ADJ
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
best	O	_	well	ADV
-	O	_	-	PUNCT
appreciated	O	_	appreciate	VERB
mov	O	_	mov	NOUN
ements	O	_	ement	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
thém	O	_	thém	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_Times_ms_1885-505_1_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:The following works have been performed in their entirety during the season : Mendelssohn’s ‘Elijah, ‘Hear my Prayer,” ** Loreley,” 98th Psalm, ‘‘ Ave Maria,” and ‘As the Hart pants,” Spohr’s ‘God, Thou art Great,” Gaul’s Sacred Cantata, ‘The Holy City,” and C.].Stevens’s Anthem “ Sing, O Heavens,” selections having been also given from “ The Messiah,” “ Israel in Egypt,” ‘The Seasons,” ‘St. Paul,” “Samson,” and the “Song of Miriam.”
The	O	_	the	DET
following	O	_	follow	VERB
works	O	_	work	NOUN
have	O	_	have	AUX
been	O	_	be	AUX
performed	O	_	perform	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
their	O	_	their	PRON
entirety	O	_	entirety	NOUN
during	O	_	during	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
season	O	_	season	NOUN
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
Mendelssohn	O	_	Mendelssohn	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
Elijah	B-music	Q1329006	Elijah	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
Hear	B-music	NIL	hear	VERB
my	I-music	NIL	my	PRON
Prayer	I-music	NIL	prayer	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
*	O	_	*	PUNCT
*	O	_	*	PUNCT
Loreley	B-music	NIL	Loreley	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
98th	B-music	Q1326476	98th	ADJ
Psalm	I-music	Q1326476	Psalm	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
Ave	B-music	NIL	Ave	PROPN
Maria	I-music	NIL	Maria	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
As	B-music	NIL	as	SCONJ
the	I-music	NIL	the	DET
Hart	I-music	NIL	hart	NOUN
pants	I-music	NIL	pant	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
Spohr	O	_	Spohr	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
God	B-music	NIL	God	PROPN
,	I-music	NIL	,	PUNCT
Thou	I-music	NIL	thou	PRON
art	I-music	NIL	art	VERB
Great	I-music	NIL	great	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
Gaul	B-person	Q4723319	Gaul	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
Sacred	B-music	NIL	sacred	ADJ
Cantata	I-music	NIL	Cantata	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
The	O	_	the	DET
Holy	O	_	Holy	PROPN
City	O	_	City	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
C.	O	_	C.	PROPN
]	O	_	]	PUNCT
.Stevens	O	_	.Stevens	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
Anthem	O	_	Anthem	PROPN
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Sing	B-music	NIL	sing	VERB
,	I-music	NIL	,	PUNCT
O	I-music	NIL	o	INTJ
Heavens	I-music	NIL	heaven	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
selections	O	_	selection	NOUN
having	O	_	having	AUX
been	O	_	be	AUX
also	O	_	also	ADV
given	O	_	give	VERB
from	O	_	from	ADP
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
The	B-music	NIL	the	DET
Messiah	I-music	NIL	Messiah	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Israel	B-music	NIL	Israel	PROPN
in	I-music	NIL	in	ADP
Egypt	I-music	NIL	Egypt	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
The	B-music	NIL	the	DET
Seasons	I-music	NIL	season	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
St.	B-music	NIL	St.	PROPN
Paul	I-music	NIL	Paul	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Samson	B-music	NIL	Samson	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Song	B-music	NIL	song	NOUN
of	I-music	NIL	of	ADP
Miriam	I-music	NIL	Miriam	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT

#document_id:the_Musical_Times_ms_1884-493_4_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Besides the artists already mentioried we are promised Madame Adelina Patti, Madame Sembrich, Madame Maria Durand, Mdlle. De Vere (her first appearance at the Royai Italian Opera), Madame Scalchi, Mdlle. Reggiani, and Mdille. Tremelli; Signor Nicolini, Signor Marconi, M. Soulacroix, Signor Mierzwinski, Signor Cotogni, M. Devoyod, Signor De Reszké, Signor Monti, and Signor Novara.
Besides	O	_	besides	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
artists	O	_	artist	NOUN
already	O	_	already	ADV
mentioried	O	_	mentiorie	VERB
we	O	_	we	PRON
are	O	_	be	AUX
promised	O	_	promise	VERB
Madame	O	_	Madame	PROPN
Adelina	B-person	Q234166	Adelina	PROPN
Patti	I-person	Q234166	Patti	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Madame	B-person	Q265698	Madame	PROPN
Sembrich	I-person	Q265698	Sembrich	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Madame	B-person	NIL	Madame	PROPN
Maria	I-person	NIL	Maria	PROPN
Durand	I-person	NIL	Durand	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Mdlle	B-person	Q19998212	Mdlle	PROPN
.	I-person	Q19998212	.	PUNCT
De	I-person	Q19998212	De	PROPN
Vere	I-person	Q19998212	Vere	PROPN
(	O	_	(	PUNCT
her	O	_	her	PRON
first	O	_	first	ADJ
appearance	O	_	appearance	NOUN
at	O	_	at	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Royai	O	_	Royai	PROPN
Italian	O	_	Italian	PROPN
Opera	O	_	Opera	PROPN
)	O	_	)	PUNCT
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Madame	B-person	Q7553670	Madame	PROPN
Scalchi	I-person	Q7553670	Scalchi	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Mdlle	B-person	NIL	Mdlle	PROPN
.	I-person	NIL	.	PUNCT
Reggiani	I-person	NIL	Reggiani	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Mdille	B-person	NIL	Mdille	PROPN
.	I-person	NIL	.	PUNCT
Tremelli	I-person	NIL	Tremelli	PROPN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
Signor	B-person	Q3083329	Signor	PROPN
Nicolini	I-person	Q3083329	Nicolini	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Signor	O	_	Signor	PROPN
Marconi	B-person	Q5479431	Marconi	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
M.	B-person	NIL	M.	PROPN
Soulacroix	I-person	NIL	Soulacroix	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Signor	B-person	NIL	Signor	PROPN
Mierzwinski	I-person	NIL	Mierzwinski	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Signor	B-person	Q2562468	Signor	PROPN
Cotogni	I-person	Q2562468	Cotogni	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
M.	B-person	NIL	M.	PROPN
Devoyod	I-person	NIL	Devoyod	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Signor	B-person	Q924545	Signor	PROPN
De	I-person	Q924545	De	PROPN
Reszké	I-person	Q924545	Reszké	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Signor	B-person	NIL	Signor	PROPN
Monti	I-person	NIL	Monti	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Signor	B-person	NIL	Signor	PROPN
Novara	I-person	NIL	Novara	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_Times_ms_1885-505_4_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:A capital programme on the 23rd drew a full audience, the general public beinz attracted by Beethoven's Rasoumowski Quartet in F, No. 1, and Tartini'’s ‘ Trillo del Diavolo,”” and musicians by Grieg’s Sonata in F, for piano and violin, Op. 8.
A	O	_	a	DET
capital	O	_	capital	NOUN
programme	O	_	programme	NOUN
on	O	_	on	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
23rd	O	_	23rd	NOUN
drew	O	_	draw	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
full	O	_	full	ADJ
audience	O	_	audience	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
general	O	_	general	ADJ
public	O	_	public	NOUN
beinz	O	_	beinz	NOUN
attracted	O	_	attract	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
Beethoven	B-person	Q255	Beethoven	PROPN
's	O	_	's	PART
Rasoumowski	B-music	Q3927118	Rasoumowski	PROPN
Quartet	I-music	Q3927118	Quartet	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
F	B-nan	NIL	F	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
No	O	_	no	NOUN
.	O	_	.	NOUN
1	O	_	1	NUM
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Tartini	B-person	Q108555	Tartini	PROPN
'	O	_	'	PART
’s	O	_	’s	PART
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
Trillo	B-music	Q2641249	Trillo	PROPN
del	I-music	Q2641249	del	PROPN
Diavolo	I-music	Q2641249	Diavolo	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
musicians	O	_	musician	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
Grieg	B-person	NIL	Grieg	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
Sonata	O	_	sonata	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
F	B-nan	NIL	F	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
for	O	_	for	ADP
piano	O	_	piano	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
violin	O	_	violin	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Op	O	_	Op	PROPN
.	O	_	.	NOUN
8	O	_	8	NUM
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1827-002_ms_3
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:After this, we had: Les Néces de Gamache, a comic opera, in three acts, by Mercadante, translated and arranged by Messrs. Sauvage and Dupin, and adapted to the stage by M. Guénée: we suppose it would be unpardonable to omit any of these important particulars, as the authors always show such marked anxiety te bring them befere the world.
After	O	_	after	ADP
this	O	_	this	PRON
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
we	O	_	we	PRON
had	O	_	have	VERB
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
Les	O	_	Les	PROPN
Néces	O	_	Néces	PROPN
de	O	_	de	ADP
Gamache	O	_	Gamache	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
a	O	_	a	DET
comic	O	_	comic	ADJ
opera	O	_	opera	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
three	O	_	three	NUM
acts	O	_	act	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
by	O	_	by	ADP
Mercadante	B-person	Q313980	Mercadante	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
translated	O	_	translate	VERB
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
arranged	O	_	arrange	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
Messrs.	O	_	Messrs.	NOUN
Sauvage	O	_	Sauvage	PROPN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Dupin	O	_	Dupin	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
adapted	O	_	adapt	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
stage	O	_	stage	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
M.	B-person	NIL	M.	PROPN
Guénée	I-person	NIL	Guénée	PROPN
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
we	O	_	we	PRON
suppose	O	_	suppose	VERB
it	O	_	it	PRON
would	O	_	would	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
unpardonable	O	_	unpardonable	ADJ
to	O	_	to	PART
omit	O	_	omit	VERB
any	O	_	any	PRON
of	O	_	of	ADP
these	O	_	these	DET
important	O	_	important	ADJ
particulars	O	_	particular	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
as	O	_	as	SCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
authors	O	_	author	NOUN
always	O	_	always	ADV
show	O	_	show	VERB
such	O	_	such	ADJ
marked	O	_	marked	ADJ
anxiety	O	_	anxiety	NOUN
te	O	_	te	PART
bring	O	_	bring	VERB
them	O	_	they	PRON
befere	O	_	befere	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
world	O	_	world	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:Dwight's Journal of Music_1857-001_ms_1
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:One man may lived, who ean read the heart, and whose power was not: based upon, his own experience ‘but if so, we may well call William Shakspeare superhuman, THenee it was that whiffe i m ~Rossint’s “ Barber of Seville,” ar Cimarosa’s « Seeret Marriage.”
One	O	_	one	NUM
man	O	_	man	NOUN
may	O	_	may	AUX
lived	O	_	lived	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
who	O	_	who	PRON
ean	O	_	ean	X
read	O	_	read	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
heart	O	_	heart	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
whose	O	_	whose	DET
power	O	_	power	NOUN
was	O	_	be	AUX
not	O	_	not	PART
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
based	O	_	base	VERB
upon	O	_	upon	SCONJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
his	O	_	his	PRON
own	O	_	own	ADJ
experience	O	_	experience	NOUN
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
if	O	_	if	SCONJ
so	O	_	so	ADV
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
we	O	_	we	PRON
may	O	_	may	AUX
well	O	_	well	ADV
call	O	_	call	VERB
William	B-person	Q692	William	PROPN
Shakspeare	I-person	Q692	Shakspeare	PROPN
superhuman	O	_	superhuman	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
THenee	O	_	thenee	X
it	O	_	it	PRON
was	O	_	be	AUX
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
whiffe	O	_	whiffe	NOUN
i	O	_	i	NOUN
m	O	_	m	NOUN
~Rossint	O	_	~Rossint	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Barber	B-music	Q208659	Barber	PROPN
of	I-music	Q208659	of	ADP
Seville	I-music	Q208659	Seville	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
ar	O	_	ar	PROPN
Cimarosa	B-person	Q191775	Cimarosa	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
«	O	_	«	PUNCT
Seeret	B-music	NIL	Seeret	PROPN
Marriage	I-music	NIL	Marriage	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT

#document_id:The Musical Times_1852-098_ms_2
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:In making this announcement, the Editor has the pleasure to state that he has entered into an engagement with the Proprietor of the joint publication, “THe Musica Times anp Musica, Review,’’ and that his energies will henceforth be devoted to the encouragement of the musical art, and to the advocacy of the interests of its professors, in a more comprehensive sphere.
In	O	_	in	ADP
making	O	_	make	VERB
this	O	_	this	DET
announcement	O	_	announcement	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
Editor	O	_	Editor	PROPN
has	O	_	have	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
pleasure	O	_	pleasure	NOUN
to	O	_	to	PART
state	O	_	state	VERB
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
he	O	_	he	PRON
has	O	_	have	AUX
entered	O	_	enter	VERB
into	O	_	into	ADP
an	O	_	an	DET
engagement	O	_	engagement	NOUN
with	O	_	with	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Proprietor	O	_	proprietor	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
joint	O	_	joint	ADJ
publication	O	_	publication	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
THe	B-magazine	Q1757371	THe	PROPN
Musica	I-magazine	Q1757371	Musica	PROPN
Times	I-magazine	Q1757371	Times	PROPN
anp	I-magazine	Q1757371	anp	PROPN
Musica	I-magazine	Q1757371	Musica	PROPN
,	I-magazine	Q1757371	,	PUNCT
Review	I-magazine	Q1757371	Review	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
’’	O	_	’'	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
that	O	_	that	SCONJ
his	O	_	his	PRON
energies	O	_	energy	NOUN
will	O	_	will	AUX
henceforth	O	_	henceforth	ADV
be	O	_	be	AUX
devoted	O	_	devote	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
encouragement	O	_	encouragement	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
musical	O	_	musical	ADJ
art	O	_	art	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
advocacy	O	_	advocacy	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
interests	O	_	interest	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
its	O	_	its	PRON
professors	O	_	professor	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
more	O	_	more	ADV
comprehensive	O	_	comprehensive	ADJ
sphere	O	_	sphere	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_Times_ms_1896-646_4_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:I have read with much pleasure the account you have given in THE Musica Times of the early introduction of Bach’s organ music in England, and perhaps you may be interested to know a little personal reminiscence I have of Jacob’s duet arrangement of the ‘St. Ann’s Fugue.”
I	O	_	I	PRON
have	O	_	have	AUX
read	O	_	read	VERB
with	O	_	with	ADP
much	O	_	much	ADJ
pleasure	O	_	pleasure	NOUN
the	O	_	the	DET
account	O	_	account	NOUN
you	O	_	you	PRON
have	O	_	have	AUX
given	O	_	give	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
THE	O	_	the	DET
Musica	O	_	Musica	PROPN
Times	O	_	Times	PROPN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
early	O	_	early	ADJ
introduction	O	_	introduction	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Bach	B-person	Q1339	Bach	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
organ	O	_	organ	NOUN
music	O	_	music	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
England	B-country	Q21	England	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
perhaps	O	_	perhaps	ADV
you	O	_	you	PRON
may	O	_	may	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
interested	O	_	interested	ADJ
to	O	_	to	PART
know	O	_	know	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
little	O	_	little	ADJ
personal	O	_	personal	ADJ
reminiscence	O	_	reminiscence	NOUN
I	O	_	I	PRON
have	O	_	have	VERB
of	O	_	of	ADP
Jacob	B-person	Q1339	Jacob	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
duet	O	_	duet	NOUN
arrangement	O	_	arrangement	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
St.	O	_	St.	PROPN
Ann	O	_	Ann	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
Fugue	O	_	Fugue	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT

#document_id:the_Musical_Times_ms_1902-708_1_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Dr. Chrysander, who was evidently unaware of the above statement in Parker’s Penny Post, draws certain conclusions from some memoranda by Handel in regard to the names and number of singers; but these probably refer to a subsequent concert performance.
Dr.	B-person	NIL	Dr.	PROPN
Chrysander	I-person	NIL	Chrysander	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
who	O	_	who	PRON
was	O	_	be	AUX
evidently	O	_	evidently	ADV
unaware	O	_	unaware	ADJ
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
above	O	_	above	ADJ
statement	O	_	statement	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
Parker	O	_	Parker	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
Penny	B-newspaper	NIL	Penny	PROPN
Post	I-newspaper	NIL	Post	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
draws	O	_	draw	VERB
certain	O	_	certain	ADJ
conclusions	O	_	conclusion	NOUN
from	O	_	from	ADP
some	O	_	some	DET
memoranda	O	_	memorandum	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
Handel	B-person	Q7302	Handel	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
regard	O	_	regard	NOUN
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
names	O	_	name	NOUN
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
number	O	_	number	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
singers	O	_	singer	NOUN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
these	O	_	these	PRON
probably	O	_	probably	ADV
refer	O	_	refer	VERB
to	O	_	to	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
subsequent	O	_	subsequent	ADJ
concert	O	_	concert	NOUN
performance	O	_	performance	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1823-002_ms_2
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:As the first musical establishment in London, this Theatre will To the Italian Opera every nation in Europe ‘is indebted. for its purest taste in voca! music, and so long as it continues to be encouraged, a progressive improvement must be expected in this, the highest branch of the art.
As	O	_	as	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
first	O	_	first	ADJ
musical	O	_	musical	ADJ
establishment	O	_	establishment	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
London	B-city	Q84	London	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
this	O	_	this	DET
Theatre	O	_	Theatre	PROPN
will	O	_	will	AUX
To	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Italian	O	_	Italian	PROPN
Opera	O	_	Opera	PROPN
every	O	_	every	DET
nation	O	_	nation	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
Europe	B-continent	Q46	Europe	PROPN
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
is	O	_	be	AUX
indebted	O	_	indebted	ADJ
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
for	O	_	for	ADP
its	O	_	its	PRON
purest	O	_	pure	ADJ
taste	O	_	taste	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
voca	O	_	voca	X
!	O	_	!	PUNCT
music	O	_	music	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
so	O	_	so	ADV
long	O	_	long	ADV
as	O	_	as	SCONJ
it	O	_	it	PRON
continues	O	_	continue	VERB
to	O	_	to	PART
be	O	_	be	AUX
encouraged	O	_	encourage	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
a	O	_	a	DET
progressive	O	_	progressive	ADJ
improvement	O	_	improvement	NOUN
must	O	_	must	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
expected	O	_	expect	VERB
in	O	_	in	ADP
this	O	_	this	PRON
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
highest	O	_	high	ADJ
branch	O	_	branch	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
art	O	_	art	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_World_ms_1843-040_1_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Adolphe Adam, the composer of Le Postillon de Lonjumeau, was the first to apostrophize the acquirements of M. Vivier, ina Jengthened artiele in the France Wusicale ; he has been followed by the rest of them, and last week , in the Gazelle AZusicale, we find a paper by Maurice Bourges, which makes M. Vivier something less than a demi-god, and extols his qualifications, in language, which applied to would be M. Bourges melts Paganini himself, nothing short of hyperbolical.
Adolphe	B-person	Q189544	Adolphe	PROPN
Adam	I-person	Q189544	Adam	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
composer	O	_	composer	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
Le	B-music	Q468633	Le	PROPN
Postillon	I-music	Q468633	Postillon	PROPN
de	I-music	Q468633	de	X
Lonjumeau	I-music	Q468633	Lonjumeau	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
was	O	_	be	AUX
the	O	_	the	DET
first	O	_	first	ADJ
to	O	_	to	PART
apostrophize	O	_	apostrophize	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
acquirements	O	_	acquirement	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
M.	B-person	NIL	M.	PROPN
Vivier	I-person	NIL	Vivier	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
ina	O	_	ina	X
Jengthened	O	_	jengthene	VERB
artiele	O	_	artiele	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
France	B-newspaper	Q3209228	France	PROPN
Wusicale	I-newspaper	Q3209228	Wusicale	PROPN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
he	O	_	he	PRON
has	O	_	have	AUX
been	O	_	be	AUX
followed	O	_	follow	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
rest	O	_	rest	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
them	O	_	they	PRON
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
last	O	_	last	ADJ
week	O	_	week	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Gazelle	B-magazine	Q3428721	Gazelle	PROPN
AZusicale	I-magazine	Q3428721	AZusicale	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
we	O	_	we	PRON
find	O	_	find	VERB
a	O	_	a	DET
paper	O	_	paper	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
Maurice	B-person	Q73128734	Maurice	PROPN
Bourges	I-person	Q73128734	Bourges	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
which	O	_	which	PRON
makes	O	_	make	VERB
M.	B-person	NIL	M.	PROPN
Vivier	I-person	NIL	Vivier	PROPN
something	O	_	something	PRON
less	O	_	less	ADJ
than	O	_	than	ADP
a	O	_	a	DET
demi	O	_	demi	NOUN
-	O	_	-	NOUN
god	O	_	god	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
extols	O	_	extol	VERB
his	O	_	his	PRON
qualifications	O	_	qualification	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
in	O	_	in	ADP
language	O	_	language	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
which	O	_	which	PRON
applied	O	_	apply	VERB
to	O	_	to	PART
would	O	_	would	AUX
be	O	_	be	AUX
M.	O	_	M.	PROPN
Bourges	O	_	Bourges	PROPN
melts	O	_	melt	VERB
Paganini	B-person	Q66075	Paganini	PROPN
himself	O	_	himself	PRON
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
nothing	O	_	nothing	PRON
short	O	_	short	ADJ
of	O	_	of	ADP
hyperbolical	O	_	hyperbolical	ADJ
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:Dwight's Journal of Music_1860-012_ms_1
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:In 1824 her family was residing at Paris, where she received, musical instruction from M. Fétis, at present:director of the Brussels Conse rratoire, author of the Biographie Universelle de Musiciens, together with many didactic works, and compos at that time prefessor in the Conservatoire of ‘Paris.
In	O	_	in	ADP
1824	O	_	1824	NUM
her	O	_	her	PRON
family	O	_	family	NOUN
was	O	_	be	AUX
residing	O	_	reside	VERB
at	O	_	at	ADP
Paris	B-city	Q90	Paris	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
where	O	_	where	SCONJ
she	O	_	she	PRON
received	O	_	receive	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
musical	O	_	musical	ADJ
instruction	O	_	instruction	NOUN
from	O	_	from	ADP
M.	B-person	Q523581	M.	PROPN
Fétis	I-person	Q523581	Fétis	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
at	O	_	at	ADP
present	O	_	present	ADJ
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
director	O	_	director	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Brussels	O	_	Brussels	PROPN
Conse	O	_	Conse	PROPN
rratoire	O	_	rratoire	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
author	O	_	author	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Biographie	B-publication	Q28007160	Biographie	PROPN
Universelle	I-publication	Q28007160	Universelle	PROPN
de	I-publication	Q28007160	de	ADP
Musiciens	I-publication	Q28007160	Musiciens	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
together	O	_	together	ADV
with	O	_	with	ADP
many	O	_	many	ADJ
didactic	O	_	didactic	ADJ
works	O	_	work	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
compos	O	_	compo	NOUN
at	O	_	at	ADP
that	O	_	that	DET
time	O	_	time	NOUN
prefessor	O	_	prefessor	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
Conservatoire	O	_	Conservatoire	PROPN
of	O	_	of	ADP
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
Paris	B-city	Q90	Paris	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The Harmonicon_1826-048_ms_3
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:With respect to the pieces given, the following seven are new to our theatre: Die sieben Midchen, Das Hausgesinde, Der Unsichibare, Die Ochsenmenuett, Staberls Reise-abentheuer, ‘and Le Macon by Auber; Macbeth in Schiller’s translation, ‘and with Reichardt’s music, is also new to us.
With	O	_	with	ADP
respect	O	_	respect	NOUN
to	O	_	to	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
pieces	O	_	piece	NOUN
given	O	_	give	VERB
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
the	O	_	the	DET
following	O	_	following	ADJ
seven	O	_	seven	NUM
are	O	_	be	AUX
new	O	_	new	ADJ
to	O	_	to	ADP
our	O	_	our	PRON
theatre	O	_	theatre	NOUN
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
Die	B-music	NIL	die	PRON
sieben	I-music	NIL	sieben	ADJ
Midchen	I-music	NIL	Midchen	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Das	O	_	Das	PROPN
Hausgesinde	O	_	Hausgesinde	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Der	B-music	NIL	Der	PROPN
Unsichibare	I-music	NIL	Unsichibare	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Die	B-music	NIL	Die	PROPN
Ochsenmenuett	I-music	NIL	Ochsenmenuett	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Staberls	B-music	NIL	Staberls	PROPN
Reise	I-music	NIL	Reise	PROPN
-	I-music	NIL	-	PUNCT
abentheuer	I-music	NIL	abentheuer	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Le	B-music	Q1809978	Le	PROPN
Macon	I-music	Q1809978	Macon	PROPN
by	O	_	by	ADP
Auber	B-person	Q157672	Auber	PROPN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
Macbeth	B-work-of-art	Q130283	Macbeth	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
Schiller	B-person	Q22670	Schiller	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
translation	O	_	translation	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
‘	O	_	'	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
with	O	_	with	ADP
Reichardt	B-person	Q213742	Reichardt	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
music	O	_	music	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
is	O	_	be	AUX
also	O	_	also	ADV
new	O	_	new	ADJ
to	O	_	to	ADP
us	O	_	we	PRON
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:Dwight's Journal of Music_1857-001_ms_2
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:«The opera is in three acts, music composed by Bishop, then -a young man, and beeomting very popular, “ Clari, or the. Maid of Milan,” was avted for the first time at Covent Garden Theatre, May 8 1823, w ith the following east: .
«	O	_	«	PUNCT
The	O	_	the	DET
opera	O	_	opera	NOUN
is	O	_	be	AUX
in	O	_	in	ADP
three	O	_	three	NUM
acts	O	_	act	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
music	O	_	music	NOUN
composed	O	_	compose	VERB
by	O	_	by	ADP
Bishop	B-person	Q1200639	Bishop	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
then	O	_	then	ADV
-a	O	_	-a	PRON
young	O	_	young	ADJ
man	O	_	man	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
beeomting	O	_	beeomting	NOUN
very	O	_	very	ADV
popular	O	_	popular	ADJ
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
“	O	_	"	PUNCT
Clari	O	_	Clari	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
or	O	_	or	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
Maid	B-music	Q581474	Maid	PROPN
of	I-music	Q581474	of	ADP
Milan	I-music	Q581474	Milan	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
”	O	_	"	PUNCT
was	O	_	be	AUX
avted	O	_	avte	VERB
for	O	_	for	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
first	O	_	first	ADJ
time	O	_	time	NOUN
at	O	_	at	ADP
Covent	B-building	Q55018	Covent	PROPN
Garden	I-building	Q55018	Garden	PROPN
Theatre	I-building	Q55018	Theatre	PROPN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
May	O	_	May	PROPN
8	O	_	8	NUM
1823	O	_	1823	NUM
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
w	O	_	w	X
ith	O	_	ith	X
the	O	_	the	DET
following	O	_	follow	VERB
east	O	_	east	NOUN
:	O	_	:	PUNCT
.	O	_	.	PUNCT

#document_id:The_Musical_Times_ms_1885-505_3_
#document_date:NaN
#sent_text:Whether this kind of thing is permissible is open to question; but the audience settled the matter in the affirmative by encoring the performer. Miss Zimmermann gave Mendelssohn’s familiar Caprice in E, Op. 33, and Mr. Santley sang two equally familiar airs by Handel.
Whether	O	_	whether	SCONJ
this	O	_	this	DET
kind	O	_	kind	NOUN
of	O	_	of	ADP
thing	O	_	thing	NOUN
is	O	_	be	AUX
permissible	O	_	permissible	ADJ
is	O	_	be	AUX
open	O	_	open	ADJ
to	O	_	to	ADP
question	O	_	question	NOUN
;	O	_	;	PUNCT
but	O	_	but	CCONJ
the	O	_	the	DET
audience	O	_	audience	NOUN
settled	O	_	settle	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
matter	O	_	matter	NOUN
in	O	_	in	ADP
the	O	_	the	DET
affirmative	O	_	affirmative	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
encoring	O	_	encore	VERB
the	O	_	the	DET
performer	O	_	performer	NOUN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
Miss	B-person	Q4693137	Miss	PROPN
Zimmermann	I-person	Q4693137	Zimmermann	PROPN
gave	O	_	give	VERB
Mendelssohn	B-person	Q46096	Mendelssohn	PROPN
’s	O	_	’s	PART
familiar	O	_	familiar	ADJ
Caprice	B-music	Q105081984	Caprice	PROPN
in	O	_	in	ADP
E	O	_	e	NOUN
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
Op	B-nan	NIL	op	NOUN
.	I-nan	NIL	.	NOUN
33	I-nan	NIL	33	NUM
,	O	_	,	PUNCT
and	O	_	and	CCONJ
Mr.	B-person	Q521746	Mr.	PROPN
Santley	I-person	Q521746	Santley	PROPN
sang	O	_	sing	VERB
two	O	_	two	NUM
equally	O	_	equally	ADV
familiar	O	_	familiar	ADJ
airs	O	_	air	NOUN
by	O	_	by	ADP
Handel	B-person	Q7302	Handel	PROPN
.	O	_	.	PUNCT
